<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Memos</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/</link><description>Some examples of what Open Terms Archive exposes, as identified by independent contributors.</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Telegram expands its age eligibility requirement to Australian users</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/telegram-expands-its-age-eligibility-requirement-to-australian-users/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>tam kien duong</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/telegram-expands-its-age-eligibility-requirement-to-australian-users/</guid><description>Telegram expanded its age eligibility requirement by adding Australia to the regions where users must be at least 18 years old to sign up, alongside the EU and the United Kingdom.&amp;#xA;The wording was also revised. Whereas the previous policy referred to “citizens of EU countries and the United Kingdom,” linking the restriction to nationality, the updated text applies to “users,” making the requirement dependent on the user’s location rather than citizenship.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Telegram ▪ Terms of Service ▪ January 7, 2026&lt;/p>&lt;p>Telegram &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/eec51f63d0fe52a2b4c3a23a5544fc4b52dbb79b">expanded&lt;/a> its age eligibility requirement &lt;strong>by adding Australia&lt;/strong> to the regions where users must be at least 18 years old to sign up, alongside the EU and the United Kingdom.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The wording was also revised. Whereas the previous policy referred to “citizens of EU countries and the United Kingdom,” linking the restriction to nationality, the updated text applies to “users,” making the requirement dependent on the &lt;strong>user’s location rather than citizenship&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.aph.gov.au/Parliamentary_Business/Bills_LEGislation/Bills_Search_Results/Result?bId=r6680">Australia&amp;rsquo;s Online Safety Act 2021&lt;/a> introduced age verification. Telegram was &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/feb/24/australian-esafety-telegram-fine-reporting-delay">fined&lt;/a> AUD 957,780 for non-compliance in February 2025. Since November, Telegram has been &lt;a href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/telegram-sues-australia-over-age-102715194.html">challenging&lt;/a> the fine on technical, legal and freedom of speech grounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telegram_%28software%29">Telegram&lt;/a> is a messaging application founded by Nikolai and Pavel Durov, two Russian entrepreneurs. Telegram has come under intense scrutiny around the world for being a platform that &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telegram_%28software%29#Criticism">facilitates many illegal activities&lt;/a>, including &lt;a href="https://www.404media.co/how-telegrams-founder-pavel-durov-became-a-culture-war-martyr/">the sale of illegal pornography and the drug trade&lt;/a>. Marketed as a privacy-focused messaging app, it also benefits Durov&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/europe/russia-telegram-kremlin-pavel-durov/2020/06/27/4928ddd4-b161-11ea-98b5-279a6479a1e4_story.html">anti-Putin reputation&lt;/a> and the company’s &lt;a href="https://www.404media.co/telegram-changes-policy-says-it-will-provide-user-data-to-authorities/">&amp;ldquo;refusal to hand over data in response to lawful orders&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>. Since then, and especially since Durov’s arrest by the French authorities, Telegram has started &lt;a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/en/pixels/article/2025/01/08/telegram-gave-more-user-data-to-french-authorities-after-founder-s-arrest_6736824_13.html">cooperating&lt;/a> with government agencies and &lt;a href="https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/telegram-expands-forbidden-uses-data-disclosure-authorities/">modifying&lt;/a> its policies.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>YouTube allows viewers in Taiwan to buy Jewels</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-allows-viewers-in-taiwan-to-buy-jewels/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>tam kien duong</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-allows-viewers-in-taiwan-to-buy-jewels/</guid><description>On January 6, 2026, YouTube expanded its Virtual Items Program to viewers in Taiwan. Previously, eligibility was described using the term “US viewers”, which was ambiguous and did not clearly specify whether it was based on residency or location. The updated language clarifies that eligibility is based on the user’s location.&amp;#xA;The Virtual Items Program is a microtransaction mechanism that allows viewers to purchase bundles of Jewels, which they can transform into digital items. These items can then be sent as tokens of ‘appreciation in real-time’ during vertical live streams. Items received by the creator, as Rubies, are converted into Google AdSense credit at a rate of 1 Ruby per USD0.01. Google AdSense is an online advertising program provided by Google platform.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>YouTube ▪ Content Monetisation Policy ▪ January 6, 2026&lt;/p>&lt;p>On January 6, 2026, YouTube &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/54d22c276ceaf361b3fe95fd6e10bd52aefc7729">expanded&lt;/a> its &lt;em>Virtual Items Program&lt;/em> to viewers in Taiwan. Previously, eligibility was described using the term “US viewers”, which was ambiguous and did not clearly specify whether it was based on residency or location. The updated language clarifies that eligibility is based on the user’s location.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/15427201?hl=en&amp;amp;sjid=18056223716587959946-EU">Virtual Items Program&lt;/a> is a microtransaction mechanism that allows viewers to purchase bundles of &lt;em>Jewels&lt;/em>, which they can transform into digital items. These items can then be sent as tokens of ‘appreciation in real-time’ during vertical live streams. Items received by the creator, as &lt;em>Rubies,&lt;/em> are converted into Google AdSense credit at a rate of 1 Ruby per USD0.01. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_AdSense">Google AdSense&lt;/a> is an online advertising program provided by Google platform.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>AliExpress allows the sale of decorative plants in Poland, France, Germany, Italy and Spain</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/aliexpress-allows-the-sale-of-decorative-plants-in-poland-france-germany-italy-and-spain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>tam kien duong</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/aliexpress-allows-the-sale-of-decorative-plants-in-poland-france-germany-italy-and-spain/</guid><description>On January 4, 2026, AliExpress modified its Marketplace Sellers Conditions to allow local sellers in Poland, Germany, France, Italy, and Spain to sell live ornamental plants. The policy now permits these sellers to ‘sell live plants within the country if they meet the compliance requirements’. An announcement released on October 14, 2025 stated that ‘plant seeds, living plants only for ornamental purposes rather than food purposes’ are authorized. ‘Agricultural and vegetable’ products are still prohibited for sale&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>AliExpress ▪ Marketplace Sellers Conditions ▪ January 4, 2026&lt;/p>&lt;p>On January 4, 2026, AliExpress &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/bfe3524765ce18753a0799134da4a3f6153de9e6">modified&lt;/a> its Marketplace Sellers Conditions to &lt;strong>allow local sellers in Poland, Germany, France, Italy, and Spain to sell live ornamental plants&lt;/strong>. The policy now permits these sellers to ‘sell live plants within the country if they meet the compliance requirements’. An announcement released on October 14, 2025 &lt;a href="https://rule.aliexpress.com/rule-channels/37978936/240465709?spm=a2q5o.26736372.0.0.4d0140aaK4GDHB">stated&lt;/a> that ‘plant seeds, living plants only for ornamental purposes rather than food purposes’ are authorized. ‘Agricultural and vegetable’ products are still prohibited for sale&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AliExpress is a serious competitor for Amazon in the field of online shopping. The Chinese company has recently started delivering fresh food in &lt;a href="https://pulse.mk.co.kr/news/english/11449009">South Korea&lt;/a> and in &lt;a href="https://retailtechinnovationhub.com/home/2025/7/8/aliexpress-launches-hourly-delivery-within-greater-london-for-household-essentials-food-and-drink">London&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In November 2023, the European Union was already &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/eu-asks-alibabas-aliexpress-information-illegal-products-sold-its-platform-2023-11-06/">investigating&lt;/a> AliExpress for distributing ‘illegal products such as fake medicines, non-compliant food, and ineffective dietary supplements’.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Facebook now uses AI interactions to personalise experiences and ads</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-now-uses-ai-interactions-to-personalise-experiences-and-ads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Saumyaa Naidu</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-now-uses-ai-interactions-to-personalise-experiences-and-ads/</guid><description>Facebook included AI at Meta as a Meta Product to which its privacy policy now applies. The generative AI features and experiences across Meta Company Products are collectively referred to as AI at Meta. The platform will collect information from interactions with AI at Meta, and also share it on Meta Products and with integrated partners. These interactions will include prompts, responses received, actions requested, and feedback given to AI. Facebook will also record information provided by others about a user to AI at Meta, including messages and content that the user may have shared.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Facebook ▪ Privacy Policy ▪ December 28, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>Facebook &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/1abd1ab7b0ba845929d2802f8cb8eec72d0c0948">included&lt;/a> AI at Meta as a Meta Product to which its privacy policy now applies. The generative AI features and experiences across Meta Company Products are collectively referred to as AI at Meta. The platform will collect information from interactions with AI at Meta, and also share it on Meta Products and with integrated partners. These interactions will include prompts, responses received, actions requested, and feedback given to AI. Facebook will also record information provided by others about a user to AI at Meta, including messages and content that the user may have shared.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the revised policy, information collected across Products will be used to personalise features, content, and ads in AI at Meta, among other Meta Products. The information will also be shared with other Meta Companies to personalise features and integrations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Furthermore, interactions with AI at Meta and related metadata such as content and messages will be used for purposes such as personalising and improving Meta Products, promoting safety, integrity, and security, providing measurement, analytics, and business services, personalising ads on Meta Audience Network, undertaking research for social good, and sharing information with others, including law enforcement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information collected from user activities on Meta products including posts, comments, audio etc, interactions with AI at Meta, and information from partners, vendors, and third parties, will all be used for the newly introduced purpose of developing and improving AI at Meta. Facebook removed the clarification that it will not share personally identifying information, such as username, unless included in messages to the AIs, with third-parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides the updates in use of data from AI at Meta, Facebook has also expanded information collection on users’ connections and interactions both on and off Meta Products, and on the online or in person use of third party products and services. The platform added data providers as a third-party public source for datasets which will now be additionally used for undertaking analytics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The policy no longer provides details of information used to decide which ads and commercial content to show. It also removed factors that influence the personalisation of Facebook Feed and links to manage it. The policy clarifies now that search engines and other third parties use public content about a user (name, username, profile picture, etc.) according to their own terms and policies, not Meta&amp;rsquo;s. Finally, for non-account holders, Facebook added that it can remove content that violates their terms and policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meta is among the several major platforms that have &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/11/24/are-tech-companies-using-your-private-data-to-train-ai-models">introduced&lt;/a> updates related to AI data use, including Google, LinkedIn, and Open AI. Given this shift, researchers have &lt;a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2025/10/ai-chatbot-privacy-concerns-risks-research">highlighted&lt;/a> concerns such as privacy risks, manipulation using vulnerabilities, and a &lt;a href="https://bostoninstituteofanalytics.org/blog/meta-will-begin-using-ai-chatbot-conversations-to-target-ads/">lack of users&amp;rsquo; control&lt;/a> over their data and experience on platforms.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>TikTok updates its Developer Terms to introduce Commercial Content Library access, clarify research purposes, and reorganize core definitions</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-updates-its-developer-terms-to-introduce-commercial-content-library-access-clarify-research-purposes-and-reorganize-core-definitions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Asma Sifaoui</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-updates-its-developer-terms-to-introduce-commercial-content-library-access-clarify-research-purposes-and-reorganize-core-definitions/</guid><description>TikTok updated its Developer Terms of Service with targeted but consequential revisions that clarified access conditions, introduced a new data category tied to the EU Digital Services Act, and restructured core definitions governing developer use of TikTok services.&amp;#xA;The update strengthens the acceptance clause by replacing permissive language with an explicit prohibition. Where the prior version stated that users who do not agree to the terms should not access the Developer Services, the revised text now states that users who do not agree are not permitted to access or use them. This change sharpens the contractual boundaries around consent and access.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>TikTok ▪ Developer Terms ▪ December 26, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>TikTok &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/4663035ba671ce711211525453090089f9225fa0">updated&lt;/a> its Developer Terms of Service with targeted but consequential revisions that clarified access conditions, introduced a new data category tied to the EU Digital Services Act, and restructured core definitions governing developer use of TikTok services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The update strengthens the acceptance clause by replacing permissive language with an explicit prohibition. Where the prior version stated that users who do not agree to the terms should not access the Developer Services, the revised text now states that users who do not agree are not permitted to access or use them. This change sharpens the contractual boundaries around consent and access.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TikTok also introduces a new defined dataset, “CCL Data,” referring to advertising and commercial content made available through the Commercial Content Library API. Alongside this, the company adds a new definition of “CCL Purposes,” explicitly framing the use of this data as supporting supervision and research into risks associated with online advertising, including illegal ads, manipulation, and disinformation with foreseeable impacts on public health, security, civic discourse, political participation, and equality. The Commercial Content Library API itself is newly defined and explicitly linked to &lt;a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32022R2065#art_39">Article 39&lt;/a> of the EU Digital Services Act, signaling alignment with statutory transparency obligations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition, the Definitions section is reorganized and renumbered without materially changing the substance of most existing terms. Definitions for Developer Content, End Users, TikTok API, Developer Documentation, Developer Services, Sample Code, SDKs, TikTok Services, and TikTok Information are reinserted in a revised order, with minor wording adjustments but no substantive expansion of rights or obligations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the changes do not broaden developer permissions but instead formalize a compliance-oriented data access pathway tied to EU law, clarify enforcement language around acceptance of the terms, and structurally reorganize definitions to accommodate the newly introduced Commercial Content Library framework.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Instagram begins use of AI interactions to personalise experiences and ads</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-begins-use-of-ai-interactions-to-personalise-experiences-and-ads/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Saumyaa Naidu</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-begins-use-of-ai-interactions-to-personalise-experiences-and-ads/</guid><description>Instagram included AI at Meta as a Meta Product to which its privacy policy now applies. The platform will collect information from a user’s interactions with AI at Meta, and information provided by others about a user to AI at Meta, including messages and content that the user may have shared. In the revised policy, information collected across Products will be used to personalise features, content, and ads in AI at Meta, among other Meta Products. The information will also be shared with other Meta Companies to personalise features and integrations. </description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Instagram ▪ Privacy Policy ▪ December 16, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>Instagram &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/2b539280359100f59d72663ac2aaa8913e3e5f29">included&lt;/a> AI at Meta as a Meta Product to which its privacy policy now applies. The platform will collect information from a user’s interactions with AI at Meta, and information provided by others about a user to AI at Meta, including messages and content that the user may have shared. In the revised policy, information collected across Products will be used to personalise features, content, and ads in AI at Meta, among other Meta Products. The information will also be shared with other Meta Companies to personalise features and integrations. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Furthermore, interactions with AI at Meta and related metadata such as content and messages will be used for purposes such as personalising and improving Meta Products, promoting safety, integrity, and security, providing measurement, analytics, and business services, personalising ads on Meta Audience Network, undertaking research for social good, and sharing information with others, including law enforcement. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information collected from user activities on Meta products including posts, comments, audio etc, interactions with AI at Meta, and information from partners, vendors, and third parties, will all be used for the newly introduced purpose of developing and improving AI at Meta. Instagram removed the clarification that it will not share personally identifying information, such as username, unless included in messages to the AIs, with third-parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides the updates in use of data from AI at Meta, Instagram has also expanded information collection on users’ connections and interactions both on and off Meta Products, and on the online or in person use of third party products and services. The policy no longer provides details of information used to decide which ads and commercial content to show. The policy clarifies that search engines and other third parties use public content about a user (name, username, profile picture, etc.) according to their own terms and policies, not Meta&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meta is among the several major platforms that have &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2025/11/24/are-tech-companies-using-your-private-data-to-train-ai-models">introduced&lt;/a> updates related to AI data use, including Google, LinkedIn, and Open AI. Given this shift, researchers have &lt;a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2025/10/ai-chatbot-privacy-concerns-risks-research">highlighted&lt;/a> concerns such as privacy risks, manipulation using vulnerabilities, and a &lt;a href="https://bostoninstituteofanalytics.org/blog/meta-will-begin-using-ai-chatbot-conversations-to-target-ads/">lack of users&amp;rsquo; control&lt;/a> over their data and experience on platforms.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pinterest is replacing pharmacies in its list of prohibited ads with casinos</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-is-replacing-pharmacies-in-its-list-of-prohibited-ads-with-casinos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>tam kien duong</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-is-replacing-pharmacies-in-its-list-of-prohibited-ads-with-casinos/</guid><description>In a minor modification to its Commercial Terms, Pinterest replaced an advertising category that was prohibited from being shown in Qatar and Saudi Arabia. ‘Brick-and-mortar casinos’ are replacing ‘brick-and-mortar pharmacies’.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Pinterest ▪ Commercial Terms ▪ December 13, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>In a minor modification to its Commercial Terms, Pinterest &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/8e804db6dd6b38e78a28e8ee3e050c2645342434">replaced&lt;/a> an advertising category that was prohibited from being shown in Qatar and Saudi Arabia. ‘Brick-and-mortar casinos’ are replacing ‘brick-and-mortar pharmacies’.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pinterest permits alcoholic beverage advertisements</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-permits-alcoholic-beverage-advertisements/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>tam kien duong</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-permits-alcoholic-beverage-advertisements/</guid><description>Pinterest updated its Marketplace Sellers Conditions to permit the promotion of alcoholic beverages in its shopping ads. The change mentions that alcohol advertising must comply with local jurisdictions, such as those regarding legal age restrictions. It also includes a comprehensive list of countries where such advertisements are prohibited. Lastly, it sets down global rules outlining the prohibition of targeting minors and restricting positive alcohol consumption discourse.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Pinterest ▪ Marketplace Sellers Conditions ▪ December 12, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>Pinterest &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/5fcad164ce434a01d3730e1d3ffcb24a354c847b">updated&lt;/a> its &lt;em>Marketplace Sellers Conditions&lt;/em> to permit the promotion of alcoholic beverages in its shopping ads. The change mentions that alcohol advertising must comply with local jurisdictions, such as those regarding legal age restrictions. It also includes a comprehensive list of countries where such advertisements are prohibited. Lastly, it sets down global rules outlining the prohibition of targeting minors and restricting positive alcohol consumption discourse.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wikipedia clarifies rules for accessing and disclosing temporary account IP addresses</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/wikipedia-clarifies-rules-for-accessing-and-disclosing-temporary-account-ip-addresses/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Asma Sifaoui</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/wikipedia-clarifies-rules-for-accessing-and-disclosing-temporary-account-ip-addresses/</guid><description>Wikipedia updated its Privacy Policy section on the use of temporary account IP addresses, specifically on refining how access, disclosure, and misuse of this information are governed. The changes do not expand who can access IP addresses, but they clarify permissible uses, add procedural detail, and tighten safeguards around disclosure.&amp;#xA;The update reiterates that temporary account IP addresses may only be used for investigation, discovery, and enforcement related to vandalism, abuse, harassment, spam, and other policy violations. It explicitly allows the use of IP auto-reveal functionality during investigations, provided the automatically revealed IP addresses are used solely for these enforcement purposes. The revised text also removes language suggesting that access must be strictly “as-needed,” replacing it with a clearer emphasis on purpose limitation and compliance with applicable local policies.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Wikipedia ▪ Privacy Policy ▪ December 11, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>Wikipedia &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/8be928c66b15f7a67d1b1c60cad7479e7de21e75">updated&lt;/a> its Privacy Policy section on the use of temporary account IP addresses, specifically on refining how access, disclosure, and misuse of this information are governed. The changes do not expand who can access IP addresses, but they clarify permissible uses, add procedural detail, and tighten safeguards around disclosure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The update reiterates that temporary account IP addresses may only be used for investigation, discovery, and enforcement related to vandalism, abuse, harassment, spam, and other policy violations. It explicitly allows the use of IP auto-reveal functionality during investigations, provided the automatically revealed IP addresses are used solely for these enforcement purposes. The revised text also removes language suggesting that access must be strictly “as-needed,” replacing it with a clearer emphasis on purpose limitation and compliance with applicable local policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wikipedia also refined restrictions on disclosure. While users with access rights may still make limited disclosures when blocking fake accounts, also referred to as &amp;ldquo;sockpuppets&amp;rdquo; within the wikipedia community, or performing administrative actions, the policy now explicitly prohibits directly connecting temporary accounts to their associated IP addresses in block reasons or similar public contexts. Disclosures are framed as permissible only when reasonably necessary for enforcement or investigation, and IP addresses must be removed if later determined to be unnecessary or disclosed in error.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The update also clarifies consequences for misuse. An unnecessary or mistaken disclosure alone is no longer framed as grounds for immediate removal of access. Instead, the policy specifies that repeated patterns, intentional misuse, or local community consensus are required to justify revoking access to temporary account IP addresses. Parallel language is added for users with manually granted access, aligning standards across access pathways.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Snapchat adds minimum age requirements in Australia</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/snapchat-adds-minimum-age-requirements-in-australia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Saumyaa Naidu</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/snapchat-adds-minimum-age-requirements-in-australia/</guid><description>Snapchat added Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) requirements of the Online Safety Act 2021 for users in Australia. In order to comply with the SMMA, where “users under 16 years of age must not hold accounts on certain services”, the platform will verify the country of residence and age of the user based on information collected. This would include date of birth, IP address, behavioural information about interaction with Snapchat, information about content created, interactions with My AI (Snapchat’s chatbot), metadata, and information about friends on the platform. Snapchat further requires users to undertake age verification measures using a third-party provider called k-ID. Snapchat will only receive a “yes/no” result on whether the user is above 16, based on which access will be granted. For users below 16, the account will be locked and Snapchat will not receive any personal information provided during the k-ID verification process. </description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Snapchat ▪ Privacy Policy ▪ December 9, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>Snapchat &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-au-versions/commit/0ef0689dfbcb33848c2f3de747c04c154daabac3">added&lt;/a> Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) requirements of the Online Safety Act 2021 for users in Australia. In order to comply with the SMMA, where “users under 16 years of age must not hold accounts on certain services”, the platform will verify the country of residence and age of the user based on information collected. This would include date of birth, IP address, behavioural information about interaction with Snapchat, information about content created, interactions with My AI (Snapchat’s chatbot), metadata, and information about friends on the platform. Snapchat further requires users to undertake age verification measures using a third-party provider called k-ID. Snapchat will only receive a “yes/no” result on whether the user is above 16, based on which access will be granted. For users below 16, the account will be locked and Snapchat will not receive any personal information provided during the k-ID verification process. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) law came into effect on December 10, 2025, in Australia and has &lt;a href="https://globalvoices.org/2025/12/15/australias-under-16-social-media-ban-under-microscope-at-home-and-abroad/">garnered&lt;/a> criticism from teenagers, activists, and politicians. Reddit has also filed a lawsuit against the Australian government to oppose these requirements.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>TikTok will not be accessible to children below 16 in Australia</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-will-not-be-accessible-to-children-below-16-in-australia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Saumyaa Naidu</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-will-not-be-accessible-to-children-below-16-in-australia/</guid><description>TikTok added minimum age requirements in compliance with the Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) law under the Online Safety Act 2021 in Australia. Under the terms for Australian residents, the platform specified that “TikTok is not directed at children under the age of 16”. The policy also includes links to report users below the age of 16, and to raise complaints and escalate to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC) if needed. </description><content:encoded>&lt;p>TikTok ▪ Privacy Policy ▪ December 9, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>TikTok &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-au-versions/commit/a0a6ba8e5aa366a0b4d914ac66077dcab2931c9e">added&lt;/a> minimum age requirements in compliance with the Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) law under the Online Safety Act 2021 in Australia. Under the terms for Australian residents, the platform specified that “TikTok is not directed at children under the age of 16”. The policy also includes links to report users below the age of 16, and to raise complaints and escalate to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC) if needed. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) law came into effect on December 10, 2025, in Australia and has &lt;a href="https://globalvoices.org/2025/12/15/australias-under-16-social-media-ban-under-microscope-at-home-and-abroad/">garnered&lt;/a> criticism from teenagers, activists, and politicians. Reddit has also filed a lawsuit against the Australian government to oppose these requirements.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>X adds minimum user age of 16 in Australia</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-adds-minimum-user-age-of-16-in-australia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Saumyaa Naidu</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-adds-minimum-user-age-of-16-in-australia/</guid><description>X specified that users only above the age of 16 can use an X account in Australia. The update has been made in order to comply with the Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) requirements of the Online Safety Act 2021 under Australian law. The SMMA prohibits certain age-restricted social media platforms from letting people under the age of 16 create or hold an account. While outlining its age-verification approaches, X has listed using existing information such as self-attested age, ID verification, legacy verified public figures, account creation date, and verified government or organisational accounts. When these are unavailable, X will use email address-based estimation to verify the age. If these methods are unsuccessful, the platform will require users to submit a government-issued ID, which will be used to verify their age by artificial intelligence systems. </description><content:encoded>&lt;p>X ▪ Community Guidelines ▪ December 9, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>X &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-au-versions/commit/a948db2063fa4e17f16988b999ca7b62452e599c">specified&lt;/a> that users only above the age of 16 can use an X account in Australia. The update has been made in order to comply with the Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) requirements of the Online Safety Act 2021 under Australian law. The SMMA prohibits certain age-restricted social media platforms from letting people under the age of 16 create or hold an account. While outlining its age-verification approaches, X has listed using existing information such as self-attested age, ID verification, legacy verified public figures, account creation date, and verified government or organisational accounts. When these are unavailable, X will use email address-based estimation to verify the age. If these methods are unsuccessful, the platform will require users to submit a government-issued ID, which will be used to verify their age by artificial intelligence systems.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>X has also added terms to handle the information collected during the verification process. It will use ID details for age verification purposes only and destroy the data collected within 31 days. When an account holder is determined to be below 16 years of age, they will be unable to use an X account. Further, the policy details out mechanisms to appeal an age assurance decision and to report a suspected underage account. Similar to the previous version of the policy, accounts belonging to known minors between the ages of 16 and 18 years will be allowed ,with certain restrictions on visibility of posts and receiving direct messages. &lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Social Media Minimum Age (SMMA) law came into effect on December 10, 2025, in Australia and has &lt;a href="https://globalvoices.org/2025/12/15/australias-under-16-social-media-ban-under-microscope-at-home-and-abroad/">garnered&lt;/a> criticism from teenagers, activists, and politicians. Reddit has also filed a lawsuit against the Australian government to oppose these requirements.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>YouTube details out criteria for educational, artistic, and public interest exceptions to violating content</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-details-out-criteria-for-educational-artistic-and-public-interest-exceptions-to-violating-content/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Saumyaa Naidu</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-details-out-criteria-for-educational-artistic-and-public-interest-exceptions-to-violating-content/</guid><description>YouTube expanded on its criteria for exceptions to content violating community guidelines. It clarified that in some cases, content with educational, documentary, scientific, or artistic (EDSA) context including public interest content will be considered an exception to otherwise prohibited content. This was updated in several sections of the community guidelines including Nudity &amp;amp;amp; Sexual Content Policy, Child Safety policy, Suicide, Self-Harm, and Eating Disorders policy, Harmful or Dangerous Content policy, Hate Speech policy, and Misinformation policies.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>YouTube ▪ Community Guidelines ▪ December 4, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>YouTube &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/c2052c3843124de40812bd065df9a842a62137f4">expanded&lt;/a> on its criteria for exceptions to content violating community guidelines. It clarified that in some cases, content with educational, documentary, scientific, or artistic (EDSA) context including public interest content will be considered an exception to otherwise prohibited content. This was updated in several sections of the community guidelines including Nudity &amp;amp; Sexual Content Policy, Child Safety policy, Suicide, Self-Harm, and Eating Disorders policy, Harmful or Dangerous Content policy, Hate Speech policy, and Misinformation policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the EDSA exception was already stated in many of these sections, YouTube also added public interest content such as “congressional or parliamentary proceedings, campaign speeches, or debates over ongoing government actions” to the list of exceptions and age-restricted content.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Starlink globalizes its policies and adds specificities for Nigeria and South Korea</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/starlink-globalizes-its-policies-and-adds-specificities-for-nigeria-and-south-korea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>tam kien duong</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/starlink-globalizes-its-policies-and-adds-specificities-for-nigeria-and-south-korea/</guid><description>On November 26, 2025, Starlink updated its privacy policy to become a global privacy policy. Long overdue, the last official version was from May 1, 2023. The updated policy applies to all services provided by Starlink, not just its website. It now allows using de-identified data ‘from and about’ users to be used for ‘any purpose, including improving our services, to the extent permitted by applicable law’. Data will be disclosed to government regulators or law enforcement agencies in order ‘to protect any person from death or serious bodily injury’.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>Starlink ▪ Privacy Policy ▪ November 26, 2025 - December 4, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>On November 26, 2025, Starlink &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/f0ad253188913e4877d5cf277d4264bf1fbaf2c6">updated&lt;/a> its privacy policy to become a global privacy policy. Long overdue, the last official version was from May 1, 2023. The updated policy applies to all services provided by Starlink, not just its website. It now allows using de-identified data ‘from and about’ users to be used for ‘any purpose, including improving our services, to the extent permitted by applicable law’. Data will be disclosed to government regulators or law enforcement agencies in order ‘to protect any person from death or serious bodily injury’.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, specific privacy policies for &lt;a href="https://www.starlink.com/legal/documents/DOC-DF-1906-75496-66">Nigeria&lt;/a> have also been incorporated. On December 4, another change &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/7b319573075aea7f6dc00f5746b4dac2076cd2df">introduced&lt;/a> a dedicated set for &lt;a href="https://starlink.com/legal/documents/DOC-DF-1909-87689-76">South Korea&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These modifications occur in the backdrop of the involvement of US tech companies as an extension of US diplomacy. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starlink">Starlink&lt;/a> is a satellite internet service provider operated by Starlink Services, LLC, a subsidiary of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SpaceX">SpaceX&lt;/a>, a US company owned by Elon Musk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rest of World, an independent media focusing on tech and power in global majority, has previously &lt;a href="https://restofworld.org/2025/musk-starlink-trump-doge/">highlighted&lt;/a> the link between Trump’s attention and new Starlink contracts with other countries. Nigeria has been under scrutiny due to allegations of persecution against Christian communities. The United States has &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/nov/01/trump-nigeria-christian-persecution">threatened&lt;/a> to intervene. In late October 2025, President Donald Trump &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/south-korea-award-trump-its-highest-medal-gift-him-golden-crown-2025-10-29/">made&lt;/a> a visit to South Korea. Since then, South Korean airlines have &lt;a href="https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/business/companies/20251205/starlink-service-expands-among-korean-shippers-airlines">signed&lt;/a> contracts with Starlink to offer in-flight internet to their passengers. Additionally, home internet services were introduced to the South Korean household market at the start of December.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The US Department of Defense &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starlink_in_the_Russian-Ukrainian_War">began funding&lt;/a> the provision of Starlink service to Ukrainian forces during the ongoing Russian invasion of Ukraine started in February 2022. But it also came with some controversies of intervention when Starlink &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigations/musk-ordered-shutdown-starlink-satellite-service-ukraine-retook-territory-russia-2025-07-25/">decided&lt;/a> to shut down the service during a Ukrainian strike.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>X expands and restructures its Civic-Integrity Policy</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-expands-and-restructures-its-civic-integrity-policy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Asma Sifaoui</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-expands-and-restructures-its-civic-integrity-policy/</guid><description>X has revised its Civic Integrity policy with substantial changes to how it defines civic processes and how it structures its rules against misleading or suppressive content. The update reorganizes the section under the new title “Civic Integrity” and introduces a clearer, more formal definition of what constitutes a civic process. X now explicitly lists political elections, censuses, major referendums, and ballot initiatives as events covered by the policy.&amp;#xA;The revised introduction outlines the policy’s purpose as addressing misleading content that could affect participation in elections or other civic processes, including information that may confuse users about how, when, or where to take part. This reframing moves the policy toward a more preventive orientation.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>X ▪ Community Guidelines ▪ November 19, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>X has &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/d39ef3f9b09a5a4d9cacf999be20c6fd2047cfc6">revised&lt;/a> its Civic Integrity policy with substantial changes to how it defines civic processes and how it structures its rules against misleading or suppressive content. The update reorganizes the section under the new title “Civic Integrity” and introduces a clearer, more formal definition of what constitutes a civic process. X now explicitly lists political elections, censuses, major referendums, and ballot initiatives as events covered by the policy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The revised introduction outlines the policy’s purpose as addressing misleading content that could affect participation in elections or other civic processes, including information that may confuse users about how, when, or where to take part. This reframing moves the policy toward a more preventive orientation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Furthermore, the policy reorganizes prohibited behavior into clearer categories, replacing earlier detailed examples with broader groupings. These include misleading information about how to participate, misleading claims about requirements or officials involved in administering civic processes, and content that could suppress or intimidate participation. Several examples, such as claims about polling places being closed, police activity near voting sites, or disruptions at voting locations, remain present but are now integrated into streamlined categories rather than listed as isolated cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enforcement has also been rewritten. Prior statements indicating that X would apply labels to violative posts and restrict their reach have been replaced with a model that highlights Community Notes as the platform’s primary transparency tool. The update introduces a dedicated “Civic Integrity label” reserved for critical escalations rather than routine moderation, and expands the list of possible enforcement outcomes into a more structured but less prescriptive sequence. The section describing appeals has been rewritten as well, now stating that authors “can appeal” rather than “are able to submit an appeal”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, a new “How to Report” section replaces the previous footer. It directs users to the reporting flow through the “Civic Integrity” option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the revision broadens the policy’s scope, reduces specificity in prohibited examples, and reallocates enforcement toward a community-driven context rather than automatic labelling. This introduces more flexibility for X in interpreting violations while decreasing the level of detail previously available to users about how the rules would be applied.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Apple updates App Store rules on data use, age-gating, external software, and loan app disclosures</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/apple-updates-app-store-rules-on-data-use-age-gating-external-software-and-loan-app-disclosures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Asma Sifaoui</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/apple-updates-app-store-rules-on-data-use-age-gating-external-software-and-loan-app-disclosures/</guid><description>Apple introduced several notable updates across its App Store Review Guidelines and Developer Program policies.&amp;#xA;Apple now requires developers to clearly disclose where personal data will be used when sharing data with third parties. Apps may not use Apple-provided APIs or collected data to build contact databases or for advertising, and any app that shares user data without consent or violates privacy law may be removed from the App Store.&amp;#xA;The guidelines also add a new restriction stating that developers cannot reuse another developer’s icon, brand, or product name without approval. For apps offering embedded software such as HTML5 mini apps or game emulators, Apple maintains that all such software must follow App Store rules, and developers may not expose native platform APIs without Apple’s permission.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>App Store ▪ Review Guidelines ▪ November 14, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>Apple &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/e59f84cfc8f0f419c73833066c962ae3640e3410">introduced&lt;/a> several notable updates across its App Store Review Guidelines and Developer Program policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple now requires developers to clearly disclose where personal data will be used when sharing data with third parties. Apps may not use Apple-provided APIs or collected data to build contact databases or for advertising, and any app that shares user data without consent or violates privacy law may be removed from the App Store.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The guidelines also add a new restriction stating that developers cannot reuse another developer’s icon, brand, or product name without approval. For apps offering embedded software such as HTML5 mini apps or game emulators, Apple maintains that all such software must follow App Store rules, and developers may not expose native platform APIs without Apple’s permission.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A new requirement clarifies that apps must provide age-restriction mechanisms when creator content exceeds the app’s declared age rating. This aligns age-gating rules across creator- and user-generated content categories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Furthermore, Apple updated its App Store rules to explicitly include crypto exchanges in the list of highly regulated services that must be operated by a legal entity and may require geographic restrictions, thereby tightening compliance expectations for apps handling sensitive financial activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple also tightened its standards for financial-service apps: loan apps must disclose all loan terms and cannot charge an APR above 36%, ensuring clear, enforceable consumer-protection standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These updates reflect Apple’s broader trend toward enforcing stricter privacy practices, transparency in developer behavior, and heightened consumer protection within the App Store.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>LinkedIn now allows violating content if it is educational or newsworthy</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-now-allows-violating-content-if-it-is-educational-or-newsworthy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Saumyaa Naidu</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-now-allows-violating-content-if-it-is-educational-or-newsworthy/</guid><description>LinkedIn specified that it “may allow certain content that would otherwise violate these Professional Community Policies to remain on the platform if it is educational or newsworthy”. This could include graphic depictions of an occupation, content on an event like war or armed conflict, or statements or actions by public officials. The platform will determine newsworthiness by balancing the content’s potential harm against the value it brings to members. The policy also clarified that any graphic or disturbing newsworthy or educational content will include a warning screen.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>LinkedIn ▪ Community Guidelines ▪ November 7, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>LinkedIn &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/891a208f02e1b57bff516e4caa8a4ad5abeadb88#diff-88386d527dff09b9311f1e66713dff8eebbf339a52952a1b2376eb198d34a60fR44">specified&lt;/a> that it “may allow certain content that would otherwise violate these Professional Community Policies to remain on the platform if it is educational or newsworthy”. This could include graphic depictions of an occupation, content on an event like war or armed conflict, or statements or actions by public officials. The platform will determine newsworthiness by balancing the content’s potential harm against the value it brings to members. The policy also clarified that any graphic or disturbing newsworthy or educational content will include a warning screen.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>LinkedIn shares data with Microsoft and its subsidiaries to train AI models</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-shares-data-with-microsoft-and-its-subsidiaries-to-train-ai-models/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Asma Sifaoui</dc:creator><dc:creator>Saumyaa Naidu</dc:creator><dc:creator>Matti Schneider</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-shares-data-with-microsoft-and-its-subsidiaries-to-train-ai-models/</guid><description>LinkedIn updated its Privacy Policy globally to expand the scope of personal data sharing across Microsoft services1. For example, LinkedIn may receive information about user engagement in Outlook, instead of only sending its engagement data to Microsoft. The affiliates list now explicitly includes GitHub, Inc. among Microsoft-controlled entities under this personal data sharing agreement. The language regarding targeted advertising and data use across services has been refined to state that LinkedIn may use engagement data from its affiliates to improve ad-targeting tools.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>LinkedIn ▪ Privacy Policy ▪ November 4, 2025 - November 3, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>LinkedIn &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/a58058977951278dcf908f987dc2f8c307da1178">updated&lt;/a> its Privacy Policy globally to expand the scope of personal data sharing across Microsoft services&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. For example, LinkedIn may receive information about user engagement in Outlook, instead of only sending its engagement data to Microsoft. The affiliates list now explicitly includes GitHub, Inc. among Microsoft-controlled entities under this personal data sharing agreement. The language regarding targeted advertising and data use across services has been refined to state that LinkedIn may use engagement data from its affiliates to improve ad-targeting tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Within the existing purpose of AI features, LinkedIn added use of personal data points from profiles such as work and volunteer experience, people and companies you follow, and licenses and certifications, along with adding conversation data from Generative AI features (GenAI), member generated content, data related to service use, and inferences about users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-ie-versions/commit/50dcbecfd7c391c0aaa4cf0db72ffc9763f85cd3">European version&lt;/a> of the terms and conditions gives more information on the data collected and intended use, owing to GDPR requirements. There, we can see that LinkedIn removed the earlier distinction of not using personal data for training and improving their AI systems for content creation. It introduced new purposes for personal data collection and use under the “Legitimate interest” legal basis: offering content-generating GenAI features to members, training these features, and improving LinkedIn&amp;rsquo;s products and services. For these, it will use data from profiles, activities, connections and group memberships, but also &lt;strong>group activity and messages, inferences about users feedback provided on services, data provided when users request support from LinkedIn, and conversations with GenAI features&lt;/strong>. This change is applicable to residents of the EU, EEA, UK, and Switzerland. LinkedIn allows users to opt out of having their data used for this purpose at any time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-ie-versions/blob/50dcbecfd7c391c0aaa4cf0db72ffc9763f85cd3/LinkedIn/Privacy%20Policy.md?plain=1#L513">UK version&lt;/a> of the changes also makes the usage of personal data for GenAI clearer, stating that uses include “train, fine-tune, and evaluate […] Microsoft’s AI models”. It also explicitly mentions, beyond “posts, comments, articles”, company page data and job postings, that “LinkedIn video you create, LinkedIn Learning Videos and Transcripts” are used for GenAI model improvements. This is in compliance with the UK &lt;a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/uk-gdpr-guidance-and-resources/artificial-intelligence/explaining-decisions-made-with-artificial-intelligence/part-1-the-basics-of-explaining-ai/legal-framework/">GDPR requirements&lt;/a> that specify principles such as purpose limitation and data transparency. This update reflects the raging &lt;a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2025/09/12/1123562/how-do-ai-models-generate-videos/">competition&lt;/a> on video generation in the AI industry, where state of the art models like Sora from OpenAI and Veo from Google need immense amounts of video footage for training. Researchers have &lt;a href="https://hai.stanford.edu/news/privacy-ai-era-how-do-we-protect-our-personal-information">highlighted&lt;/a> that this scenario could lead to numerous privacy concerns including collection and misuse of personal information captured through training data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The differences traced in the terms for different jurisdictions based on their regulatory requirements emphasise the need for cross-jurisdiction tracking and analysis of platform policies. It also highlights the varying levels of AI regulations and enforcement across jurisdictions and how platforms respond to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>We note that Microsoft acquired LinkedIn in December 2016.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></content:encoded></item><item><title>TikTok expands data collection in Europe, the United Kingdom and Switzerland</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-expands-data-collection-in-europe-the-united-kingdom-and-switzerland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>tam kien duong</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-expands-data-collection-in-europe-the-united-kingdom-and-switzerland/</guid><description>TikTok has announced several modifications to the extent of its data collection practices in Europe, the United Kingdom, and Switzerland. The document specifies that, starting on 30 November 2025, the service will now gather &amp;amp;ldquo;precise location information from devices,&amp;amp;rdquo; whereas previous versions only allow for using &amp;amp;ldquo;approximate location.&amp;amp;rdquo; The new policy also allows data collection from &amp;amp;ldquo;interactions with websites within the in-app browser.&amp;amp;rdquo; In addition, TikTok will no longer restrict itself to collecting data from &amp;amp;ldquo;activity on and off the Platform,&amp;amp;rdquo; extending data collection to &amp;amp;ldquo;information associated with (&amp;amp;hellip;) user account[s].&amp;amp;rdquo; Lastly, TikTok will explicitly scan direct messages for safety and protection.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>TikTok ▪ Privacy Policy ▪ October 30, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>TikTok has &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-gb-versions/commit/68d0988a48b7fb7e95e8fc4763533ade9debd2e8">announced&lt;/a> several modifications to the extent of its data collection practices in Europe, the United Kingdom, and Switzerland. The document specifies that, starting on 30 November 2025, the service will now gather &amp;ldquo;precise location information from devices,&amp;rdquo; whereas previous versions only allow for using &amp;ldquo;approximate location.&amp;rdquo; The new policy also allows data collection from &amp;ldquo;interactions with websites within the in-app browser.&amp;rdquo; In addition, TikTok will no longer restrict itself to collecting data from &amp;ldquo;activity on and off the Platform,&amp;rdquo; extending data collection to &amp;ldquo;information associated with (&amp;hellip;) user account[s].&amp;rdquo; Lastly, TikTok will explicitly scan direct messages for safety and protection.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A similar document previously &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250930005637/https://www.tiktok.com/legal/page/ca/privacy-policy/en">existed&lt;/a> for Canada, but it is &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/legal/page/ca/privacy-policy/en">currently unavailable&lt;/a>. The new document also &lt;a href="https://www.tiktok.com/legal/page/global/tiktok-ad-network-privacy-policy/en">includes&lt;/a> a link to an advertisement policy specific to the UK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These additions are happening at a time when &lt;a href="https://jacobin.com/2025/10/trump-xi-jinping-china-tariffs-trade-war/">the United States and China are in the middle of a complex trade war&lt;/a>, which impacts new technologies and their supply chains, including &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/30/trump-and-xi-meet-in-south-korea-for-crunch-talks-on-trade">rare-earth metal provisioning and refinement&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TikTok, owned by the Chinese company Bytedance, is one of the fastest-growing social media platforms in the world. This growth has led to increased scrutiny from both the U.S. and Europe regarding security concerns surrounding the app’s vast user base. For example, TikTok has been &lt;a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/policies/list-designated-vlops-and-vloses#ecl-inpage-tiktok">designated&lt;/a> by the European Commission as a Very Large Online Platform (VLOP) and is therefore subject to rigorous regulations and obligations in EU and EEA jurisdictions. The European Commission has already &lt;a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/eu-accuses-meta-tiktok-of-breaching-digital-rules/">expressed concerns&lt;/a> about TikTok’s excessive data collection for advertising purposes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Biden administration had initially &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Restrictions_on_TikTok_in_the_United_States#2025_shutdown">considered banning&lt;/a> the platform due to its lack of compliance. In response, ByteDance proactively &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4g91kyjw07o">removed&lt;/a> the mobile app from both the &lt;em>Apple App Store&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Google Play Store&lt;/em>, effectively preventing US users from downloading the app for a month. Following the start of his presidency, President Donald Trump postponed the ban and has continued to delay enforcement. As of today, there are discussions about &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/19/business/trump-tiktok-deal-china.html">transferring&lt;/a> the U.S. version of the app to Oracle. It remains unclear how this could affect &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/bytedance-says-it-wont-sell-u-s-tiktok-business-61f43079?mod=article_inline&amp;amp;mod=article_inline">service integrity&lt;/a> and raise a new series of cross-jurisdictional data protection issues.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item><item><title>X no longer restricts shopping to US-based businesses</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-no-longer-restricts-shopping-to-us-based-businesses/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>tam kien duong</dc:creator><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-no-longer-restricts-shopping-to-us-based-businesses/</guid><description>X updated its rules regarding merchandise sales. It is no longer necessary to have a US-based business. It also allows state-affiliated media to sell merchandise. Selling merchandise was previously restricted to ‘Professional Account[s]’, but it’s now open to X Premium and X Premium accounts. Pricing can now be in local currency, not just in US dollars. The list of prohibited merchandise categories was extensively revised, but the scope of the policy remained unchanged.&amp;#xA;</description><content:encoded>&lt;p>X ▪ Community Guidelines ▪ October 30, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;p>X &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/e74e82155f06490f2bb7e21b6c118ba335cd4acc">updated&lt;/a> its rules regarding merchandise sales. It is no longer necessary to have a US-based business. It also allows state-affiliated media to sell merchandise. Selling merchandise was previously restricted to ‘Professional Account[s]’, but it’s now open to X Premium and X Premium accounts. Pricing can now be in local currency, not just in US dollars. The list of prohibited merchandise categories was extensively revised, but the scope of the policy remained unchanged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twitter is a social media platform whose main revenue is digital advertising. Since &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitter#Since_2022">the acquisition by Elon Musk&lt;/a> in 2022, the service has been rebranded as X. In 1999, Elon Musk already co-founded an online bank named &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X.com_%5C%28bank%5C%29">X.com&lt;/a>. It became PayPal after merging with Confinity, a bank cofounded by Peter Thiel. X.com was envisioned as a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Super-app">super-app&lt;/a> that would host an ecosystem of services, such as banking and shopping. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WeChat">WeChat&lt;/a> is the main example of a super-app in the Chinese digital ecosystem. Going beyond being an instant messaging service, WeChat allows users to purchase goods, book accommodation, and even hail a taxi.&lt;/p></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>