<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Memos on Open Terms Archive website</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/</link><description>Recent content in Memos on Open Terms Archive website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alibaba adds disease outbreaks to its disclaimer</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/alibaba-adds-disease-outbreaks-to-its-disclaimer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/alibaba-adds-disease-outbreaks-to-its-disclaimer/</guid><description>&lt;p>The impact of the Covid-19 pandemic can be read right into Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s terms of service: since May 6, 2020, the marketplace &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/ambanum/CGUs-data/commit/37503cb23">specified&lt;/a> epidemics as cases of force majeure in which it is not responsible for order delays or failures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Apple updates App Store rules on data use, age-gating, external software, and loan app disclosures</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/apple-updates-app-store-rules-on-data-use-age-gating-external-software-and-loan-app-disclosures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/apple-updates-app-store-rules-on-data-use-age-gating-external-software-and-loan-app-disclosures/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apple &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/e59f84cfc8f0f419c73833066c962ae3640e3410">introduced&lt;/a> several notable updates across its App Store Review Guidelines and Developer Program policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apple now requires developers to clearly disclose where personal data will be used when sharing data with third parties. Apps may not use Apple-provided APIs or collected data to build contact databases or for advertising, and any app that shares user data without consent or violates privacy law may be removed from the App Store.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The guidelines also add a new restriction stating that developers cannot reuse another developer’s icon, brand, or product name without approval. For apps offering embedded software such as HTML5 mini apps or game emulators, Apple maintains that all such software must follow App Store rules, and developers may not expose native platform APIs without Apple’s permission.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bluesky moves DSA contact point from Belgium to Ireland and stops accepting requests in French</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/bluesky-moves-dsa-contact-point-to-ireland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/bluesky-moves-dsa-contact-point-to-ireland/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bluesky Social &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/b1a978f22b73067d9b08ea5cf37fd752fcc6139d">relocated&lt;/a> its contact point for the Digital Services Act (DSA) competent authorities from Belgium to Ireland. This change implies that &lt;strong>requests from EU authorities will only be accepted in English, while they were previously also accepted in French&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This modification reinforces the existing trend of concentrating DSA-related responsibilities under the Irish authority Coimisiún na Meán, which already oversees many major digital platforms due to their European headquarters being located in Ireland.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Claude.ai switches to opt-out consent model for personal data usage in AI model training</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/claudeai-switches-to-opt-out-consent-model-for-personal-data-usage-in-ai-model-training/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/claudeai-switches-to-opt-out-consent-model-for-personal-data-usage-in-ai-model-training/</guid><description>&lt;p>Claude.ai &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/e59bf71c68398878e7d12ccdf99d89af5f0984ed#diff-51c25e106bedcf49c2924f4875242cdb6ca536bd26d2415726c5f59131aa0be4R73">revised&lt;/a> its Privacy Policy, &lt;strong>moving from an opt-in to an opt-out consent model&lt;/strong>. The updated terms, which go into effect on September 25, 2025, state that Input and Output data may be used to train models and improve services &lt;strong>unless users disable this setting in their account&lt;/strong>. Previously, such data was only used for training if users explicitly enabled the setting. The update also adds device location to the categories of personal data automatically collected when using the service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Copy.AI stops abiding with the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/copyai-stops-abiding-with-the-eu-us-data-privacy-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/copyai-stops-abiding-with-the-eu-us-data-privacy-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p>Copy.AI &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/c8a3f106587decf0cb6b5e0ce7695929d153a856">erased&lt;/a> from its privacy policy its commitment to abide by the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Replacing the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield, the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework allows companies to self-certify their compliance with local European laws. Personal data transfers from these jurisdictions are then deemed “adequately protected” according to the adequacy decision of the Commission of July 2023.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cursor details AI limitations and forbids some prompts</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/cursor-suggestions-limitations-no-rights-cooperation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/cursor-suggestions-limitations-no-rights-cooperation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cursor &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/b197079f729d0056f31e8d9a12ef13283773c507">added&lt;/a> a description of the limitations of suggestions generated by AI models, warning that they may contain “errors or misleading information”, lack creativity, misinterpret linguistic nuances, fail on complex tasks, or reflect biases in their training data, and that users bear all risks associated with using them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the same update, Cursor also introduced a list of use restrictions, including bans on reverse engineering, resale, data scraping, and using the service to train competing models. &lt;strong>Users are required to not send any prompt containing personal or payment data, and to report any unauthorized use and cooperate&lt;/strong> in stopping it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doubao expands behavioral data collection and establishes minimum age</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/doubao-expands-behavioral-data-collection-and-establishes-minimum-age/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/doubao-expands-behavioral-data-collection-and-establishes-minimum-age/</guid><description>&lt;p>Doubao &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/ada4e457907c93f9073efddf755c27ab3ff7ac58">expanded&lt;/a> the scope of data collection to include &amp;ldquo;input information&amp;rdquo;, explicitly encompassing dialogue content and search text. To further broaden the coverage of behavioral information, it appended &amp;ldquo;etc.&amp;rdquo; at the conclusion of enumerating such data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Doubao committed to making “every effort” to safeguard users&amp;rsquo; personal information and retaining it only “for the period necessary to provide Doubao services”. It also added the requirement that minors under the age of 14 must “obtain consent from their guardian” to use the service.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doubao starts tracking users behavioral data</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/doubao-starts-tracking-users-behavioral-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/doubao-starts-tracking-users-behavioral-data/</guid><description>&lt;p>Doubao &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/c799b6fce756dfc6894a2537db01d71d91a4f776">added&lt;/a> personalized recommendations for prompts and chatbots and personal data collection requirements, with an opt-out option.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this purpose, Doubao started collecting personal data, such as behavioral information (users’ clicks, searches, browsing, sharing…), and information provided by partners.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook bans States from denying the use of violence in an invasion</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-bans-states-from-denying-the-use-of-violence-in-an-invasion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-bans-states-from-denying-the-use-of-violence-in-an-invasion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Facebook &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/b315d25#diff-57f4f166af0a7f6e4fc8f63a103c74f5a8d47754238aad621db0eebdf4048df4R24">will no longer allow&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;governments that have instituted sustained blocks of social media to use their official departments, agencies, and embassies to deny the use of force or violent events in the context of an attack against the territorial integrity of another state.&amp;rdquo; Facebook adds that it may require additional information or context to ensure compliance with this new rule, as well as for other forms of manipulation already covered (astroturfing, government or foreign interference).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook can now remove accounts for interacting with violating content</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-can-now-remove-accounts-for-interacting-with-violating-content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-can-now-remove-accounts-for-interacting-with-violating-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>Facebook &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/8db591d1ecca55b871b200a6ac039e27cfc5eee2#diff-02024f8771e7c160c1ea6dedb238431cf8900d7c24b2ac0a13dd85c42ac3be96R1253">updated&lt;/a> the human exploitation provision in their Community Guidelines to &lt;strong>remove accounts based on their interactions with violating accounts, content, and groups&lt;/strong>. Based on the policy, violating accounts are those posting content that “recruits people for, facilitates, or exploits people through human trafficking”. Facebook will categorise interactions with such accounts as “behavioral signals” to detect and take action on violating accounts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This section of the policy no longer specifies removing content that offers jobs in areas flagged as high-risk for labor exploitation by law enforcement and local NGOs. However, it is still mentioned under the standards that require additional information and/or context to enforce. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook goes back in time</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-goes-back-in-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-goes-back-in-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>On June 14, Facebook &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/430f4a67045323a8c862808eb046b7ea8616842b">backdated&lt;/a> the last update of its terms of use: rather than 4 January 2022, when Facebook was renamed Meta, it now states that the last revision goes back to&amp;hellip; December 20, 2020, over one year earlier!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook removes clarification of default encryption of messages</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-removes-clarification-of-default-encryption-of-messages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/facebook-removes-clarification-of-default-encryption-of-messages/</guid><description>&lt;p>Facebook &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/d7f55cee17efd0d1a6611c5eccdb0f779202f2c3#diff-74c567ad17dce3e5bfefec67ace1101a23821fb7aedd8ef0d2a481a2e971a11cL13">removed&lt;/a> a clarification from its Law Enforcement Guidelines specifying the roll-out of default end-to-end encryption (E2EE) on Messenger. It also removed the explanation that it will be unable to provide “unencrypted message content as part of any response to any legal process that it receives” if a chat is protected by E2EE. The default E2EE feature was &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/meta-start-fully-encrypting-messages-facebook-instagram-wsj-2023-12-07/">implemented&lt;/a> in December 2023. &lt;strong>This change raises uncertainty about the scope of encryption and what data Facebook will disclose to law enforcement agencies when approached.&lt;/strong> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Firefox clarifies data licensing rights over user input</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/firefox-clarifies-data-licensing-rights-over-user-input/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/firefox-clarifies-data-licensing-rights-over-user-input/</guid><description>&lt;p>Firefox &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/05a73bc19d6be1d6ce9883a1b25a04592e5723d4#diff-d468411a000ad5f56b0882f257f5f4dc484275807562a28426088edb0473ec16L26-R26">updated&lt;/a> its Terms of Service to clarify the licensing rights it receives from users. Building on previous language that granted Mozilla, Firefox&amp;rsquo;s parent company, a &amp;ldquo;nonexclusive, royalty-free, worldwide license to use user input for the purpose of doing as you request with the content you input in Firefox,&amp;rdquo; the new version specifies that this data will be used specifically &amp;ldquo;for the purpose of doing as you request with the content you input in Firefox,” and that “this does not give Mozilla any ownership in that content.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google integrates its Generative AI Services terms into their standard terms</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/google-integrates-its-generative-ai-services-terms-into-their-standard-terms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/google-integrates-its-generative-ai-services-terms-into-their-standard-terms/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/5dc544475a9dd326f2ce7f107a89cb94c5f14cb6">integrated&lt;/a> all provisions of its Generative AI Additional Terms of Service into their main Terms of Service. Starting on 22 May 2024, the additional terms “no longer apply, unless you’re a business partner with a signed agreement that references these terms.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This move is emblematic of the broader industry trend that considers Generative AI as a generic component of provided tools and services, as opposed to a separate set of services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instagram adds a posting ban to protect copyright</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-adds-a-posting-ban-to-protect-copyright/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-adds-a-posting-ban-to-protect-copyright/</guid><description>&lt;p>On March 28, Instagram &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/1be4b836e3012344558b60d8f9f871bc42cfa4ca?short_path=c108c01#diff-c108c013f0b8769389f20259465cb81324e805f4334bcda6931344e16f999441">updated&lt;/a> its intellectual property community rules, prohibiting the posting of content that “facilitates copyright infringement through unauthorized devices or services.” The text presents a list of cases in which users would risk infringing the copyright of a third party or even merely “facilitating” such infringement, even if they did not intend to do so. After the previously listed cases, which include “you purchased or downloaded the content” or “you saw others post the same content,” Instagram adds that users risk infringing copyright if they “use an unauthorized streaming device or service (examples: a ‘jailbroken’ or ‘loaded’ app or service).”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instagram and Facebook can now disable accounts that like or save child abuse content</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-disables-accounts-that-like-child-abuse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-disables-accounts-that-like-child-abuse/</guid><description>&lt;p>Meta platforms Instagram and Facebook &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/0b6452bedc4000b9731c127c34dd6f4651e59794">expanded&lt;/a> the signals considered and actions taken to prevent child abuse. &lt;strong>Accounts may now be disabled entirely upon liking or saving content&lt;/strong>, whereas the previous version of the guidelines only referred to restricting access to certain products and features after “interactions” with infringing content.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instagram blocks data retrieval and clarifies what information it retrieves</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-blocks-data-retrieval-and-clarifies-what-information-it-retrieves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-blocks-data-retrieval-and-clarifies-what-information-it-retrieves/</guid><description>&lt;p>In November 2021, Instagram made several updates to its &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/9998cb21b69a222540491a81dd05be19a9785891">community rules&lt;/a>, its &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/9aaf5dbfc3b34d45d640b0c7f96dce3598c7bcd2">terms of use&lt;/a> and its &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/927ceba3865d79cd1b123d9f4b9928b8e997070c">privacy policy&lt;/a>. Among the notable developments, the platform explicitly prohibits the sale or exchange of &amp;ldquo;non-medical or pharmaceutical substances.&amp;rdquo; It says it will remove all posts promoting such products, either for sale or to indicate personal consumption, except in a healing context.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In its updated terms of service, Instagram prohibits creating accounts or using them in such a way as to retrieve information without permission, especially in an automated way. This could have an effect on the work of researchers like those of the NGO Algorithm Watch, a research project of which having already been &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://algorithmwatch.org/en/instagram-research-shut-down-by-facebook/">closed by Instagram&lt;/a> in the summer of 2021. The platform also prohibits disseminating other users’ personal information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instagram commits to informing in case of content removal</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-commits-to-informing-in-case-of-content-removal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-commits-to-informing-in-case-of-content-removal/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some progress: Instagram now &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/versions-france/commit/b8b71e45d56728242ce7c5da3e8b7ef790eec57a?short_path=311682c">announces&lt;/a> that in some cases where it removes content, the firm will notify the user and explain their options for requesting a review. Such a decision could have an impact on accounts like those of the 14 French feminist influencers who &lt;a href="https://www.ouest-france.fr/high-tech/instagram/instagram-14-feministes-assignent-facebook-en-justice-apres-la-censure-de-leurs-contenus-7181707">took the social network to court&lt;/a> last year. They accused Instagram of deleting posts or accounts without giving clear explanations of the reasons for these deletions, or tools to defend themselves. The terms of use do not, however, specify the cases in which Instagram will provide the announced information. They also warn that no information will be given if the user gravely or repeatedly violates the terms, among other situations that Meta will consider particularly serious.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instagram cross-references its data with user experience surveys</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-cross-references-its-data-with-user-experience-surveys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-cross-references-its-data-with-user-experience-surveys/</guid><description>&lt;p>Instagram goes into &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/versions-france/commit/b8b71e45d56728242ce7c5da3e8b7ef790eec57a#diff-311682cd6d20df952901439aefad05738f09eb8ca4f505b3af21ce20ff70f23aR37">more detail&lt;/a> about its use of user data. While it used to simply state that it uses the information available to us to develop, test and improve our Service, Instagram now adds that it includes “analysing the data we have about our users and understanding how people use our Services, for example by conducting surveys and testing and troubleshooting new features”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instagram removes support for tracking opt-out via mobile device settings</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-removes-tracking-optout-in-mobile-device-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-removes-tracking-optout-in-mobile-device-options/</guid><description>&lt;p>Instagram has &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/4a8e001c92a2b2a29bea609fc2b52fceef515b6c">removed&lt;/a> the option for users to opt out of interest-based ads through their mobile device settings. Previously, the document mentioned that users could control their ad tracking preferences “using Android, iOS 13 or an earlier version of iOS.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instagram restricts its ability to delete content</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-restricts-its-ability-to-delete-content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-restricts-its-ability-to-delete-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>Until now, Instagram said it would remove information shared on its platform if it believed the content to violate its terms of use, or if the firm was permitted or required to do so by law. The document &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/versions-france/commit/b8b71e45d56728242ce7c5da3e8b7ef790eec57a#diff-311682cd6d20df952901439aefad05738f09eb8ca4f505b3af21ce20ff70f23aR109">now states&lt;/a> that Instagram will only remove content on behalf of the law of the country concerned if it is &amp;ldquo;required&amp;rdquo; to do so.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Instagram takes significantly more responsibility in case of an incident</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-takes-significantly-more-responsibility-in-case-of-an-incident/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/instagram-takes-significantly-more-responsibility-in-case-of-an-incident/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the previous version of its Terms of Services, the social network stated that it provided its service as it is, unable to guarantee its ideal and safe operation at all times. Instagram disclaimed (in all caps) any express or implied warranties, including merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, title and non-infringement, and stated that it did not control the words and publications of third parties, nor those of the user, and that its liability was limited to the extent permitted by law in the event of an incident.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kick asserts control over commercialization and digital content</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/kick-asserts-control-over-commercialization-and-digital-content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/kick-asserts-control-over-commercialization-and-digital-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kick &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/b92d4f74d620b9972d4768b6315553e9499e632c#diff-a62c3f8b55814267dfa7d1f648f53d83aa299b92da6377854f61bd6b5c070d92R116">introduced new terms&lt;/a> governing how platform content and tools can be commercialized. While creators may use features such as subscriptions or gifting, the company reserves the right to withhold payments or alter the tools at its discretion. This reinforces Kick’s exclusive control over the commercial use of its service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The update also clarifies the status of &amp;ldquo;digital content&amp;rdquo; on the platform. KICKs (the in-app currency), Gifts, and subscriptions are treated as licenses rather than property. They cannot be sold, transferred, or refunded (except where required by law), and may be forfeited if an account is terminated. Kick also reserves the ability to discontinue or modify these digital items without compensation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kick restricts political activity and strengthens payment controls</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/kick-restricts-political-activity-and-strengthens-payment-controls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/kick-restricts-political-activity-and-strengthens-payment-controls/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kick &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/b92d4f74d620b9972d4768b6315553e9499e632c">expanded&lt;/a> its political activity rules to explicitly &lt;strong>prohibit using platform content or tools to make or deliver financial contributions for political purposes&lt;/strong>. This means that features such as subscriptions, gifting, or other monetization tools cannot be repurposed for campaign financing or related activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The update also clarifies that Kick may withhold payments if it determines its policies have been breached. This gives the platform broader discretion over the financial flows linked to creators’ activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LinkedIn joins Meta and Google in ban of political advertisement</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-joins-meta-and-google-in-ban-of-political-advertisement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-joins-meta-and-google-in-ban-of-political-advertisement/</guid><description>&lt;p>The LinkedIn policy banning misleading content &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/74bc03d153823a9b1412b3d871753074c67b782c">expanded&lt;/a> to include a ban on &lt;strong>sponsored &amp;ldquo;political advertisements, endorsements, or support posted in exchange for money or personal benefit&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LinkedIn is a Microsoft-owned professional networking site. It organizes itself around the sharing of resumes and the presentation of user-generated content that are displayed in an algorithmically arranged timeline. Changes and new requirements for political advertising on the platform were &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/help/lms/answer/a8013156">announced&lt;/a> earlier during the summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In 2024, the European Union &lt;a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/EN/legal-content/summary/transparency-and-targeting-of-political-advertising.html">introduced&lt;/a> the &lt;em>Transparency and Targeting of Political Advertising&lt;/em> (TTPA) regulation. It imposes specific requirements on platforms to provide data and reporting on distribution of political content through their advertising network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LinkedIn now allows violating content if it is educational or newsworthy</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-now-allows-violating-content-if-it-is-educational-or-newsworthy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-now-allows-violating-content-if-it-is-educational-or-newsworthy/</guid><description>&lt;p>LinkedIn &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/891a208f02e1b57bff516e4caa8a4ad5abeadb88#diff-88386d527dff09b9311f1e66713dff8eebbf339a52952a1b2376eb198d34a60fR44">specified&lt;/a> that it “may allow certain content that would otherwise violate these Professional Community Policies to remain on the platform if it is educational or newsworthy”. This could include graphic depictions of an occupation, content on an event like war or armed conflict, or statements or actions by public officials. The platform will determine newsworthiness by balancing the content’s potential harm against the value it brings to members. The policy also clarified that any graphic or disturbing newsworthy or educational content will include a warning screen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LinkedIn removes hate speech protections for transgender individuals</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-removes-transgender-hate-speech-protections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedin-removes-transgender-hate-speech-protections/</guid><description>&lt;p>LinkedIn &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/537447facc3a1922e77cfc7fe90b0fc69414b613#diff-88386d527dff09b9311f1e66713dff8eebbf339a52952a1b2376eb198d34a60fL313">removed&lt;/a> transgender-related protections from its policy on hateful and derogatory content. The platform &lt;strong>no longer lists “misgendering&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> or deadnaming&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> of transgender individuals” as examples of prohibited conduct&lt;/strong>. While “content that attacks, denigrates, intimidates, dehumanizes, incites or threatens hatred, violence, prejudicial or discriminatory action” is still considered hateful, addressing a person by a gender and name they ask not be designated by is not anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similarly, the platform removed “race or gender identity” from its examples of inherent traits for which negative comments are considered harassment. That qualification of harassment is now kept only for behaviour that is actively “disparaging another member’s […] perceived gender”, not mentioning race or gender identity anymore.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LinkedIn's community rules are not translated anymore</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedins-community-rules-are-not-translated-anymore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/linkedins-community-rules-are-not-translated-anymore/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since May 20, Open Terms Archive notes that LinkedIn&amp;rsquo;s Community rules are no longer accessible in French —or any other language. Those pages seem to have vanished: even when manually changing language, the page redirects to the English version of the &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/legal/professional-community-policies">Community Guidelines&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meta adds anti-suicide action</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-adds-anti-suicide-action/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-adds-anti-suicide-action/</guid><description>&lt;p>On June 13, Facebook &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/242048233610ece2729d0b39047dcd5adeb21e25">expanded&lt;/a> the target group of users receiving “help resources” to those who post “vague, potentially suicidal statements or references (including memes or photo library images about sad moods or depression) in the context of suicide or self-harm”. Meta &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/82cc72a102fc78107e7094f995e07b9e4364431d">changed&lt;/a> the same elements on Instagram.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These modifications can be read in light of the recurring questioning of Facebook’s responsiveness to suicide cases. In 2019, the company had already &lt;a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/pixels/article/2019/02/08/suicide-automutilation-instagram-et-facebook-vont-supprimer-les-contenus-explicites_5421003_4408996.html">tightened&lt;/a> the rules on its various networks after the suicide of a 14-year-old British teenager.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meta allows more nudity in a medical context</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-allows-more-nudity-in-a-medical-context/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-allows-more-nudity-in-a-medical-context/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since June 13, Facebook &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/200fae809ed553d6882bef3659b4544fac37e322#diff-f5b2499012804c371ee8d35d8a109e0b7a91f6a2d6d7736ab9857bfd331dbf68R23-R26">specifies&lt;/a> that posts with visible genitals or stimulated female nipples are acceptable if the post is about a medical or health-related issue. Meta changed the same elements in the Instagram community rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may be a further reaction to criticism of the moderation logic of the company&amp;rsquo;s platforms, which more easily allow male nipples to be shown than female ones. This has led to recurring removal of breast cancer prevention campaigns (as in &lt;a href="https://www.lequotidiendumedecin.fr/actus-medicales/sante-publique/ces-seins-que-facebook-ne-saurait-voir">2014&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/le-monde/article/2016/10/12/mammographie-et-facebook-du-choix-d-image-et-de-ses-consequences_5995671_4586753.html">2016&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.lepoint.fr/high-tech-internet/facebook-une-moderation-a-geometrie-variable-21-07-2018-2238056_47.php">2018&lt;/a>, and even &lt;a href="https://www.blogdumoderateur.com/facebook-conseil-surveillance-moderation-contenus-litigieux/">2021&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meta expands reach against child exploitation</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-expands-reach-against-child-exploitation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-expands-reach-against-child-exploitation/</guid><description>&lt;p>The section on child exploitation for both Facebook and Instagram &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/0396436542fa7ef8dd8ae4dd02ff0ed5500e08a2">expanded&lt;/a> to cover not only publications that exploit minors, but also “any activity” related to such acts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This opens up the question of moderation of private discussions, as social platforms show difficulties in managing content related to child abuse —as recently as late March, the New York Times &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/03/31/business/meta-child-sexual-abuse.html">showed&lt;/a> that moderation remains very light in this area, even though platforms are supposed to list this type of content and &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/3/31/23005576/facebook-content-moderators-child-sexual-abuse-material-csam-policy">report it&lt;/a> to authorities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meta removes many hate speech protections</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-dampens-hate-speech-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-dampens-hate-speech-policy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Meta &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/a90e9d276cda1ca23878fd2b2df7cc066d549c20">rewrote&lt;/a> the “hate speech” section of its Community Guidelines, significantly broadening the content allowed on its platforms Facebook, Instagram and Threads. The rewritten section is now called “hateful conduct” and removes the statement that hate speech “creates an environment of intimidation and exclusion”. It also removes every mention to “offline violence” that could result from online hate speech.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of all, this rewrite adds some clear permissions:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>We do allow allegations of mental illness or abnormality when based on gender or sexual orientation&lt;/strong>, given political and religious discourse about &lt;em>transgenderism&lt;/em>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and homosexuality (&lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/a90e9d276cda1ca23878fd2b2df7cc066d549c20#diff-dd1aecfa753374588d9e40f891e39f556b365ad800c9713ef398255bc906aad0R1346">line 1346&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We do allow content arguing for gender-based limitations of military, law enforcement, and teaching jobs. We also allow the same content based on sexual orientation, when the content is based on religious beliefs (&lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/a90e9d276cda1ca23878fd2b2df7cc066d549c20#diff-dd1aecfa753374588d9e40f891e39f556b365ad800c9713ef398255bc906aad0R1340">line 1340&lt;/a>).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using “sex- or gender-exclusive language when people […] &lt;strong>call for exclusion or use insulting language in the context of discussing political or religious topics, such as when discussing transgender rights, immigration, or homosexuality. […] Our policies are designed to allow room for these types of speech.&lt;/strong>” (&lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/a90e9d276cda1ca23878fd2b2df7cc066d549c20#diff-dd1aecfa753374588d9e40f891e39f556b365ad800c9713ef398255bc906aad0R1297">line 1297&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Beyond these additions, another revealing change is the removal of bans on specific forms of hate speech. Thanks to Open Terms Archive history tracking, we know that the following content that was previously forbidden is now &lt;strong>allowed on Instagram, Facebook and Threads starting on January 7&lt;/strong>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meta tests notification of changes for its terms</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-tests-notification-of-changes-for-its-terms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/meta-tests-notification-of-changes-for-its-terms/</guid><description>&lt;p>Meta has been busy lately: the company first &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/c57c282d0b75a479da787f7a2e8d1f9ee333d72a">added&lt;/a> a notice on May 17 announcing that it would change its Terms of Services on July 26. However, the link that was supposed to show the upcoming changes did not work. On May 25, the mention &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/a1be6b0ee835d067402513d24586e7216acf6008">disappeared&lt;/a>. The day after, a new sentence appeared in both Instagram and Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Privacy policies, stating “We have updated our policy.” On Facebook, the link leads to &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/privacy/policy">a page&lt;/a> mentioning an effect date of July 27, 2022. On Instagram, the &lt;a href="https://help.instagram.com/privacy/policy">link&lt;/a> to the new Privacy policies still does not work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Midjourney ceases free trials as it unveils subscription plans</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/midjourney-ceases-free-trials-as-it-unveils-subscription-plans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/midjourney-ceases-free-trials-as-it-unveils-subscription-plans/</guid><description>&lt;p>Midjourney &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/e2662337073ce704cbf2dd91457dc7d89ae59e36?diff=split&amp;amp;w=0">ceased&lt;/a> to refer to the entitlements of unpaid members to the assets they create. Indeed, Midjourney &lt;a href="https://help.midjourney.com/en/articles/8150088-is-there-a-free-trial">stopped&lt;/a> offering free trials. They also extended the obligation to subscribe for a Pro or Mega plan for employees of companies with over 1M$ in revenue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Midjourney amended its community guidelines, prohibiting the use of their services for illegal activities. The guidelines explicitly prohibited misleading recipients regarding the nature and origin of the created images.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Midjourney strengthens policies on intellectual property infringements</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/midjourney-strengthens-policies-on-intellectual-property-infringements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/midjourney-strengthens-policies-on-intellectual-property-infringements/</guid><description>&lt;p>Midjourney introduced an explicit &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/2cb30a2b4b338a4dffbeab9add8262cec78a3062">prohibition&lt;/a> regarding the infringement of others’ intellectual property rights in its conditions for service availability and quality, mentioning the possibility of legal action and permanent ban from the service.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously, legal action was only mentioned where the violation of intellectual property rights resulted in financial detriment to Midjourney.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mistral AI retains API prompts and outputs for 30 days</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/mistral-ai-retains-api-prompts-and-outputs-for-30-days/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/mistral-ai-retains-api-prompts-and-outputs-for-30-days/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mistral AI &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/67aef6919c6ea9094f5c3d2a909cfa975fe6dbd5">started&lt;/a> retaining prompts and outputs of API users for 30 days to “monitor abuse”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mistral starts processing personal data in USA and stops notifying of such changes</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/mistral-operates-usa-no-notification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/mistral-operates-usa-no-notification/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mistral &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/225931387dda66a4f182e78acf72feecf729136e">added&lt;/a> the USA to the locations it handles personal data on its Google Cloud Platform infrastructure, whereas it was previously limited to Ireland in the EU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In that same change, Mistral also adjusted its commitment to notify customers in case of “any changes” to the data subprocessors list, to only notify them in case of “addition or replacement of a Subprocessor”. This means it won’t notify its customers of a change like the one it just applied. Indeed, Google Cloud Platform is not added or removed from the list of subprocessors, only &lt;em>modified&lt;/em> to expand its territorial reach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Murf claims publicity rights over clients names</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/murf-claims-publicity-rights-over-clients-names/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/murf-claims-publicity-rights-over-clients-names/</guid><description>&lt;p>Murf &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/a9052d3dad068c9824c78a254a4e34cf45a1558a">added&lt;/a> a provision establishing that their users and their organisations grant Murf the right to identify them in commercial communications and case studies as Murf’s customers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Murf commits to comply with the EU-, UK- and Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/murf-commits-to-comply-with-the-eu-uk-and-swiss-us-data-privacy-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/murf-commits-to-comply-with-the-eu-uk-and-swiss-us-data-privacy-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p>Murf &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/4adb6986e2e69a76fd265dc19597a3bd19395354">committed&lt;/a> to comply with the EU-U.S. Data Protection Framework (DPF), the UK Extension of the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Incidentally, Murf ceased to disclose personal data to chat services by Crisp IM and to “affiliate partnership solution by LinkMink”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Replacing the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield, the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework approved by the adequacy decision of the European Commission &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/eN/ip_23_3721">allows&lt;/a> companies to safely transfer personal data from the EU to US, without having to put in place additional data protection safeguards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Murf streamlines licensing through identified use cases</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/murf-streamlines-licensing-through-identified-use-cases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/murf-streamlines-licensing-through-identified-use-cases/</guid><description>&lt;p>First, Murf &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/de437963aac5969e1af7bff0fb48a2aa890ad188">ceased&lt;/a> to grant a license for the use and display of their logo/marks only to identify that the Generated Content originates from Murf.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, they stopped committing to presenting usage costs in their user interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, Murf eliminated the requirement for API-users to seek approval from Murf for their descriptions of future API uses. Instead, Murf referenced a &amp;ldquo;review&amp;rdquo; process for the submitted descriptions of API usage by users.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Microsoft tracker at TikTok</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/new-microsoft-tracker-at-tik-tok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/new-microsoft-tracker-at-tik-tok/</guid><description>&lt;p>TikTok&amp;rsquo;s cookie policy has quietly evolved, with the social media company &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/versions-france/commit/b5f7e56ccfe38a03d9fcdeae9ce80e897c8f7333?short_path=d187ffa#diff-d187ffa99dddfb4f2bda567ea1fa79e37ab477ff82ddedc5dad3f18394d2f981">adding&lt;/a> Bing Pixel to its analytics and marketing data providers. The Microsoft service joins Linkedin Insight Tag (LinkedIn is also owned by Microsoft), Google Analytics and Google Ads, AppsFlyer and Facebook Pixel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenAI delays the date of entry into force of their new non-European terms of service</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-delays-the-date-of-entry-into-force-of-their-new-non-european-terms-of-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-delays-the-date-of-entry-into-force-of-their-new-non-european-terms-of-service/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenAI &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/417bd95e82655cc88182e8929eb199fb86ed4edf">postponed&lt;/a> the effective date of its new non-European terms of service from December 14 2023 to January 31 2024.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In November 13 2023, they implemented tailored terms for European and business users, added new functionalities, imposed use restrictions, limited liability, and &lt;a href="https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-enables-transfer-of-control-of-non-european-accounts-to-their-employer/">established&lt;/a> appeals mechanisms. These changes were supposed to be effective on December 14 2023.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This delay could be related to the delays in adopting the EU AI Act, which is not to happen before 2024.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenAI enables transfer of control of non-European accounts to their employer</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-enables-transfer-of-control-of-non-european-accounts-to-their-employer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-enables-transfer-of-control-of-non-european-accounts-to-their-employer/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenAI &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/2156cb964370ce4a838bc7f03b57513edf07d47e#diff-41ba34d83f6a6973f8baa1a83e44c28a8bfc58b4d5e152865c765bf95e941cc0R92">stated&lt;/a> that starting on December 14, 2023, they would notify organisations (e.g. employers) about individual accounts created with organisational email addresses. This notification allows to transfer these individual accounts to business accounts, under which organisations have access to all inputs and outputs of their generative AI services and control over the individual accounts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OpenAI also specified the set of information that they can share with third parties, such as identifiers, geolocation, network activity and commercial information for law enforcement purposes. It also specified collecting users’ personal information provided for the participation to events or for identification and clarified that they could use this data to invite users to events and inform them about services&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenAI introduces acceptable uses for API and custom GPTs</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-introduces-acceptable-uses-for-api-and-custom-gpts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-introduces-acceptable-uses-for-api-and-custom-gpts/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenAI re–&lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/8cf83dcc3d59265f901db93f5408ea98876dabc3">categorised&lt;/a> their Acceptable Use Policy into three distinct lists of prohibitions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So called “Universal” prohibitions integrated the preexisting restrictions, rephrases with added examples.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>GPT API users were prohibited from soliciting sensitive identifiers from end users, taking unauthorised action on their behalf, using third-party content without authorisation, misrepresenting the purpose of their GPT and building GPT targeting individuals under 13 years old. Violation might result in “warnings, sharing restrictions, or ineligibility for inclusion in the GPT Store or monetisation”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenAI specifies further plugin exports rules</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-specifies-further-plugin-exports-rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-specifies-further-plugin-exports-rules/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenAI &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/30f1df7d18676c57a0ae1c43c3ccdfc264535cb3">specified&lt;/a> that, as far as European (EEA and Swiss) developers were concerned, their Agreement is with OpenAI Ireland Ltd. OpenAI stopped acting as a separate controller of personal data, and developers now have to present a privacy notice to their users prior to processing their data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OpenAI also extended export restrictions to plugins “located” in countries embargoed or sanctioned by the US. This provision previously concerned only plugin owners.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OpenAI Ireland Ltd is a Dublin-based subsidiary of OpenAI &lt;a href="https://openai.com/blog/introducing-openai-dublin">set up&lt;/a> in 2023.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenAI tightens security and adds appeal mechanism for suspended accounts</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-tightens-security-and-adds-appeal-mechanism-for-suspended-accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/openai-tightens-security-and-adds-appeal-mechanism-for-suspended-accounts/</guid><description>&lt;p>OpenAI &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/d9d49b2d5e5354590a50a181cb3034b888f7d03d">prohibited&lt;/a> the modification, copying or leasing of its services as well as the circumvention of their services’ security measures. It also limited its liability by requiring users to warrant rights in their inputs and by clarifying that the output shall not be seen as factual information or as OpenAI’s opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OpenAI prohibited the use of the output for “any purpose that could have a legal or material impact on [a] person, such as making credit, educational, employment, housing, insurance, legal, medical, or other important decisions about them”.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parler opens fake address in Germany</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/parler-opens-address-germany/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/parler-opens-address-germany/</guid><description>&lt;p>American social media Parler &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/d63f05bbcbf2b0ebf087e279429a085468d7d74f#diff-f5ac1f4939c7895c9d3bdda244e6f8b6308288b30be6b9a486b142af45c739bdR88">added&lt;/a> a physical address of operations in the European Union. The address is in Köln, Germany, at the &lt;a href="https://miom.space/en/">MiOM space&lt;/a>, “a collective from Cologne with the vision of creating affordable space for creative synergies.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Little known outside of the United States of America, Parler is a social network mostly used and promoted by American conservatives. It was notably used to coordinate the 2021 storming of the US Capitol, leading to its &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/technology-55598887">suspension&lt;/a> by app stores.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Philip Morris introduces AI facial analysis for age verification</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/philipmorris-ai-face-analysis-age-verification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/philipmorris-ai-face-analysis-age-verification/</guid><description>&lt;p>Philip Morris &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/b8b2798f9a79dfb2ecf3670d917ffd275e2091#diff-871deccfe74ab8125162fba9f44e468e12e103fb6c0732c3f59df5412451ad27R26">introduced&lt;/a> the possibility of using &lt;strong>AI analysis of the user’s face&lt;/strong> via an app or online interface to perform age verification, either during sign-up or when accessing product information. The stated goal is to help control the sale of tobacco products prohibited to minors. Previously, the policy referred only to “computer analysis of your face.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The French Data Protection Authority (CNIL) &lt;a href="https://www.cnil.fr/fr/cameras-augmentees-pour-estimer-lage-dans-les-bureaux-de-tabac-la-cnil-precise-sa-position">issued a notice&lt;/a> on July 11, 2025, considering the use of “augmented cameras” for age estimation deployed in some tobacco shops to be neither necessary nor proportionate. The CNIL emphasized that such systems can in no case replace an age check based on official identification documents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pinterest bans all nudity in the US, removing exceptions for artwork or education</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-bans-all-nudity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-bans-all-nudity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pinterest has &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/5c4741bf3205c80defe32bffbe097344745b51b0">removed&lt;/a> its previous exceptions for nudity shown in artistic, scientific or historical contexts, as well as for &lt;strong>breastfeeding and mastectomy-related content&lt;/strong>. All nudity is now treated in the same way as pornography and banned. The modified section previously stated: “nudity in paintings and sculptures and in science and historical contexts is okay. Content about breastfeeding and mastectomies is also allowed.” This paragraph has been fully deleted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the time of writing, this change only appears in the &lt;a href="https://policy.pinterest.com/en/community-guidelines">American English&lt;/a> version of the Guidelines. Versions in European languages such as &lt;a href="https://policy.pinterest.com/fr/community-guidelines">French&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://policy.pinterest.com/es/community-guidelines">Spanish&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://policy.pinterest.com/de/community-guidelines">German&lt;/a> have not changed, nor the &lt;a href="https://policy.pinterest.com/en-gb/community-guidelines">British English&lt;/a> version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pinterest expands definition of prohibited political advertisement</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-expands-definition-of-prohibited-political-advertisement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-expands-definition-of-prohibited-political-advertisement/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pinterest &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/760688a44c2157ef627f6667f324f143e07fa15e">expanded&lt;/a> its restrictions on political advertising, adding cases of “ads designed or likely to influence voting behaviour within the EU” or “the outcome of a referendum or a legislative or regulatory process”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The specificity of these provisions, whereas others encompass a wide range of topics such as fundraising, merchandizing and legislation, hints at a defensive interpretation of European policies. Indeed, the EU &lt;a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/EN/legal-content/summary/transparency-and-targeting-of-political-advertising.html">regulation on transparency and targeting of political advertising (2024/900 “TTPA”)&lt;/a> came into effect on October 10, 2025, imposing transparency requirements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pinterest permits alcoholic beverage advertisements</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-permits-alcoholic-beverage-advertisements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-permits-alcoholic-beverage-advertisements/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pinterest &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/5fcad164ce434a01d3730e1d3ffcb24a354c847b">updated&lt;/a> its &lt;em>Marketplace Sellers Conditions&lt;/em> to permit the promotion of alcoholic beverages in its shopping ads. The change mentions that alcohol advertising must comply with local jurisdictions, such as those regarding legal age restrictions. It also includes a comprehensive list of countries where such advertisements are prohibited. Lastly, it sets down global rules outlining the prohibition of targeting minors and restricting positive alcohol consumption discourse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pinterest relaxes several merchant website requirements</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-relaxes-several-merchant-website-requirements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-relaxes-several-merchant-website-requirements/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pinterest &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/8d685ba4941f240bc76d0e7a6a78b901f4581a23">removed&lt;/a> a number of specific website-quality rules for merchants, including requirements for a dedicated “About Us” page, domain age minimums, and prohibitions on pop-ups or forced registration to view products. These have been replaced with a simpler standard against poor editorial content, including broken links or incomplete pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pinterest has also expanded eligibility for vehicle merchant catalogs to include Canada. It was previously limited to the United States and Germany.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pinterest removes Privacy Shield notice without updating its modification date</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-removes-privacy-shield-notice-without-updating-its-modification-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/pinterest-removes-privacy-shield-notice-without-updating-its-modification-date/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pinterest has &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/ambanum/CGUs-data/commit/a53e891ba">removed&lt;/a> a lengthy explanation of its data processing arrangements, which it said it was carrying out under the Privacy Shield then in place between the European Union and the United States. Until then, the company was committed to resolving any complaints about personal data processing and verifying as much as possible that its partners were also in compliance with the Privacy Shield. On July 21, 2020, this part was replaced by a simple sentence stating that personal data from the European Economic Area could be processed outside of it, without a commitment to manage complaints. The platform did not indicate in its &amp;ldquo;summary of recent changes&amp;rdquo; at the top of the document that it had made any such changes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protonmail clarifies its privacy policies</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/protonmail-clarifies-its-privacy-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/protonmail-clarifies-its-privacy-policies/</guid><description>&lt;p>On September 6, 2021, ProtonMail &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/510c7d65e4254e1d53221b139d7e25bb2b990510">amended&lt;/a> its privacy policies so as to clarify the effects of Swiss laws (where the company is based) on the handling of user data. So, while the company claims to offer a particularly secure email service, it may find itself &amp;ldquo;forced to share the IP address&amp;rdquo; of its users with law enforcement in criminal investigations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The day before the change, the website &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://paris-luttes.info/recit-policier-de-sainte-marthe-15258?lang=fr">Paris-Luttes.info&lt;/a> and various &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://twitter.com/OnEstLaTech/status/1434576598418796549">Internet users&lt;/a> revealed that ProtonMail had communicated the IP addresses of users linked to the Youth for Climate group to the Swiss justice system. These addresses had been requested by the French police &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.numerama.com/tech/736940-protonmail-transmet-des-adresses-ip-a-la-police-4-questions-pour-comprendre-la-polemique.html">via Europol&lt;/a>. This change mirrors what the company had indicated on &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ProtonMail/comments/pil6xi/comment/hbqha63/">Reddit&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Qwant details data shared with Microsoft</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/qwant-details-data-shared-with-microsoft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/qwant-details-data-shared-with-microsoft/</guid><description>&lt;p>On November 2, 2021, Qwant &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/549e959ef7671a194b9bedba8d12c8031c39b922">specified&lt;/a> in its privacy policy the type of data it passes on to its partner Microsoft &amp;ldquo;for the security and reliability of its services.&amp;rdquo; Among the data that the service can share with Bing, the search engine of the American giant, are the keywords searched, the type and version of the browser used, or an identifier derived from the IP address and browser information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Starlink globalizes its policies and adds specificities for Nigeria and South Korea</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/starlink-globalizes-its-policies-and-adds-specificities-for-nigeria-and-south-korea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/starlink-globalizes-its-policies-and-adds-specificities-for-nigeria-and-south-korea/</guid><description>&lt;p>On November 26, 2025, Starlink &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/f0ad253188913e4877d5cf277d4264bf1fbaf2c6">updated&lt;/a> its privacy policy to become a global privacy policy. Long overdue, the last official version was from May 1, 2023. The updated policy applies to all services provided by Starlink, not just its website. It now allows using de-identified data ‘from and about’ users to be used for ‘any purpose, including improving our services, to the extent permitted by applicable law’. Data will be disclosed to government regulators or law enforcement agencies in order ‘to protect any person from death or serious bodily injury’.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Telegram expands cooperation with authorities beyond the scope of terrorism</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/telegram-expands-forbidden-uses-data-disclosure-authorities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/telegram-expands-forbidden-uses-data-disclosure-authorities/</guid><description>&lt;p>Instant messaging service Telegram &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/9d484c869600b6e817b263b6919e20a5cd7c9c70#diff-e94a4eda2e65a52b5a52c13037a8d5f4e7f2aaffeba6dd83bb361ab973157019R235">updated its Privacy Policy&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/1a3a08b4f4a4a12fbae84197af7f4bcef0c36cc9#diff-e71804c4c17b46bdab60adfe08be9314a2cdbd028d3ce524695c844c40e643b4R9">Terms of Service&lt;/a> to deter from using its platform for illegal activities. The changes &lt;strong>allow Telegram to disclose the IP addresses and phone numbers of users following a valid order&lt;/strong> “from the relevant judicial authorities that confirms you’re a suspect in a case involving criminal activities that violate the Telegram Terms of Service”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/telegram-expands-forbidden-uses-data-disclosure-authorities/telegram-expands-forbidden-uses-data-disclosure-authorities.png" alt="Diff reading “If Telegram receives a valid order from the relevant judicial authorities that confirms you’re a suspect in a case involving criminal activities that violate the Telegram Terms of Service, we will perform a legal analysis of the request and may disclose your IP address and phone number to the relevant authorities. If any data is shared, we will include such occurrences in a quarterly transparency report published”">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terrorists and their content banned from Twitter</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/terrorists-and-their-content-banned-from-twitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/terrorists-and-their-content-banned-from-twitter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Twitter &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/4c973b7c1cfa724c3f922adb88be091957a676c1?diff=unified&amp;amp;short_path=97a74cf#diff-97a74cf182c32c5fd04a7f7ad157a172456b1e3ead0535083736fb3a8ce84c38">made clear&lt;/a> that it will delete &amp;ldquo;any accounts maintained by individual perpetrators of terrorist, violent extremist, or mass violent attacks&amp;rdquo; and that it may delete all third-party content &amp;ldquo;disseminating manifestos or other content produced by the perpetrators&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The addition can be read in light of several terrorist attacks celebrated online by their perpetrators: the Christchurch attacks had been broadcast live on the networks, as well as the Baerum massacre and then the Halle attack. After the Charlottesville attack in the United States in 2017, Twitter had been accused of not properly controlling violent speech, especially from white supremacists, and then increased its means of combating such publications. In the first half of 2021, Twitter &lt;a href="https://blog.twitter.com/en_us/topics/company/2021/transparency-19">says it has suspended&lt;/a> nearly 45,000 accounts for apology of terrorism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Threads expands profile creation beyond Instagram users</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/threads-expands-profile-creation-beyond-instagram-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/threads-expands-profile-creation-beyond-instagram-users/</guid><description>&lt;p>Threads &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/5f308804ef652e4ae29de093eeadaa2ab34fcbbb">updated&lt;/a> its Privacy Policy to remove the Instagram account requirement for new users. Users can now sign up directly with their email address or phone number, instead of needing an Instagram account as previously required.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to the change, Threads remains a service &amp;ldquo;provided by Meta Platforms Ireland Limited&amp;rdquo; that &amp;ldquo;is a part of Instagram.&amp;rdquo; The update also specifies that &amp;ldquo;if you have created a Threads profile with your email address or phone number [Meta Platforms] won’t collect and use information from any Instagram accounts you might have&amp;rdquo; to personalize the Threads experience (including ads).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TikTok expands data collection in Europe, the United Kingdom and Switzerland</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-expands-data-collection-in-europe-the-united-kingdom-and-switzerland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-expands-data-collection-in-europe-the-united-kingdom-and-switzerland/</guid><description>&lt;p>TikTok has &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-gb-versions/commit/68d0988a48b7fb7e95e8fc4763533ade9debd2e8">announced&lt;/a> several modifications to the extent of its data collection practices in Europe, the United Kingdom, and Switzerland. The document specifies that, starting on 30 November 2025, the service will now gather &amp;ldquo;precise location information from devices,&amp;rdquo; whereas previous versions only allow for using &amp;ldquo;approximate location.&amp;rdquo; The new policy also allows data collection from &amp;ldquo;interactions with websites within the in-app browser.&amp;rdquo; In addition, TikTok will no longer restrict itself to collecting data from &amp;ldquo;activity on and off the Platform,&amp;rdquo; extending data collection to &amp;ldquo;information associated with (&amp;hellip;) user account[s].&amp;rdquo; Lastly, TikTok will explicitly scan direct messages for safety and protection.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TikTok, Grok, X and Tinder appoint a legal representative based in Switzerland</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-grok-x-and-tinder-appoint-a-legal-representative-based-in-switzerland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/tiktok-grok-x-and-tinder-appoint-a-legal-representative-based-in-switzerland/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/603abfff21a8a8cde1e9aaf14a4bd8b32c86faa2">TikTok&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/GenAI-versions/commit/30f91c5645819d35c4138fcd83ff3d55773af3e5">Grok&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/contrib-versions/commit/3e4c6ab68b3b76a4ebeb923b00310af46e3c7db3">X&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/dating-versions/commit/b935d1d13923d2de1c0c4f6b402d82afd912e185">Tinder&lt;/a> added a legal representative based in Switzerland in order to comply with &lt;a href="https://www.fedlex.admin.ch/eli/cc/2022/491/en#art_14">Article 14.1&lt;/a> of the Federal Act on Data Protection (FADP), in force since September 2023, which requires companies based abroad to do so under certain cumulative conditions, in particular when large-scale and regular processing and &amp;ldquo;high risk&amp;rdquo; is carried out. Until now, the representative was the same as the one in the European Union.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) in its annual activity report &lt;a href="https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/dam/en/sd-web/F5QpKuhhYJ2O/32.%20T%C3%A4tigkeitsbericht%2020242025%20EN.pdf">published&lt;/a> on 1 July indicates to be &amp;ldquo;intervened in a targeted manner at a number of international companies that met the legal criteria in order to verify the appointment of a representative and the publication of their contact details&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter adds a tool to report spam and impersonation</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-adds-a-tool-to-report-spam-and-impersonation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-adds-a-tool-to-report-spam-and-impersonation/</guid><description>&lt;p>To report tweets that are considered spam or impersonation, users previously had to go to the tweet and then use the &amp;ldquo;report tweet&amp;rdquo; feature. &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/056ada5513abfade20cd73458e56e41abe2f80cf?short_path=3089779#diff-3089779674bfd306d704d6da138bf9e166d07e8145f5bb30e7998f2fcdf9cdcf">Now&lt;/a> they can use &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/fr/forms/authenticity/impersonation">a form&lt;/a> without having to have a Twitter account.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter adds form and statement of jurisdictional consent to its copyright claims process</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-adds-form-and-statement-of-jurisdictional-consent-to-its-copyright-claims-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-adds-form-and-statement-of-jurisdictional-consent-to-its-copyright-claims-process/</guid><description>&lt;p>On April 13, Twitter added a new condition to the issuance of a notice of dispute: it now requests the signature of a declaration of jurisdictional consent, which varies slightly depending on whether the user resides in the USA or not. For a French resident, it will therefore be necessary to attach to their information the statement of jurisdictional consent: &amp;ldquo;I consent to the jurisdiction of any court in which Twitter may be located.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter bans duplicated tweets</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-bans-duplicated-tweets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-bans-duplicated-tweets/</guid><description>&lt;p>Twitter &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/0bf0a8f85460f936781141bfaf764183867d0685">added&lt;/a> a ban on &amp;ldquo;Tweeting an existing phrase or content in a duplicative manner, whether individually or in concert with other accounts&amp;rdquo;. The change was added as Twitter updated a longer explanation of its reinforced fight against &amp;ldquo;copypastas&amp;rdquo;, both in the &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/copypasta-duplicate-content">English&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="https://help.twitter.com/fr/rules-and-policies/copypasta-duplicate-content">French&lt;/a> versions of its Platform integrity and authenticity rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such a rule should help limit astroturfing practices such as those &lt;a href="https://www.lemonde.fr/election-presidentielle-2022/video/2022/02/02/comment-des-militants-d-eric-zemmour-gonflent-artificiellement-la-presence-du-candidat-sur-twitter_6112033_6059010.html">used by Eric Zemmour&amp;rsquo;s teams&lt;/a> during the French presidential election. The decision can also be read in light of &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2022/05/08/musk-bots-on-twitter/">Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s latest statements&lt;/a>: the billionaire said he wants to remove spam bots, once his Twitter takeover is completed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter bans publishing about prisoners of war</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-bans-publishing-about-prisoners-of-war/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-bans-publishing-about-prisoners-of-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>Starting April 5, Twitter &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/d02a5431f787dcd58dc037497c06beed65c0c897?short_path=9696c1d#diff-9696c1df7dd16cea30f236779e0093c85e13ecc25835f5d9050a24b2f7479140">will ban&lt;/a> publishing &amp;ldquo;media showing prisoners of war published by government or state-affiliated media accounts&amp;rdquo; as part of their policy preventing content related to a person from being published without their consent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This could impact coverage of the conflict by media outlets like Russia Today or Sputnik, which are notoriously linked to the Russian government.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter clarifies its content suspensions rules and allows appeal</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-clarifies-its-content-suspensions-rules-and-allows-appeal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-clarifies-its-content-suspensions-rules-and-allows-appeal/</guid><description>&lt;p>Twitter &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/7460a0728476c0835c20ef973e113674b450ddc7?diff=split">clarifies&lt;/a> that content suspension for copyright infringement only happens if the violation of its Copyright Policy is “repeated”. Such a measure cannot “vary depending on the type of services” anymore. Furthermore, Twitter introduces an &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://help.twitter.com/forms/general?subtopic=suspended">appeal form&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twitter steps up control on fake accounts</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-steps-up-control-on-fake-accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/twitter-steps-up-control-on-fake-accounts/</guid><description>&lt;p>In an &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/9e02e8dc2a10ce9d388677c4ba190804bf31390f?short_path=97a74cf#diff-97a74cf182c32c5fd04a7f7ad157a172456b1e3ead0535083736fb3a8ce84c38">amendment to its Community Rules&lt;/a>, Twitter changed its section regarding account authenticity. The platform previously addressed only &amp;ldquo;impersonation&amp;rdquo; while it now targets all &amp;ldquo;false and misleading&amp;rdquo; identities, prohibiting &amp;ldquo;using false identities in a way that disrupts the experience of other users.&amp;rdquo; In its rules on &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/befac4352f27254954ef51acb9c2fa6ae0270bd5">platform manipulation&lt;/a>, Twitter switched from constraining &amp;ldquo;account and identity&amp;rdquo; to preventing &amp;ldquo;multiple accounts and coordination&amp;rdquo;, replacing the mention of &amp;ldquo;fake accounts&amp;rdquo; with a ban on &amp;ldquo;creating a very large number of accounts&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;using automation to create accounts.&amp;rdquo; Surprisingly, the platform however &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/056ada5513abfade20cd73458e56e41abe2f80cf#diff-3089779674bfd306d704d6da138bf9e166d07e8145f5bb30e7998f2fcdf9cdcfL161">removed&lt;/a> from its anti-spam tools the possibility to ask for an official ID.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unavailability of the French version of Instagram’s copyright policy</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/unavailability-of-the-french-version-of-instagrams-copyright-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/unavailability-of-the-french-version-of-instagrams-copyright-policy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Instagram seems to have trouble publishing its community rules on its French website since April 5. According to tests conducted by Open Terms Archive, some parts of the text are completely unavailable in French (the &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/00799bfa25dd930aa68af8dbbfa8ed59cda35b5f">&amp;ldquo;What happens when I submit a copyright report to Instagram ?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> page only shows an English version), or only partially translated (in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/21eae014249e946abdc9eb3609b2e3f7c3ac181d">&amp;ldquo;copyright&amp;rdquo; page&lt;/a>, the introduction and titles are in English, the rest of the text is in French)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>X adds paid subscription requirement to Creator Monetization Standards</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-adds-paid-subscription-requirement-to-creator-monetization-standards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-adds-paid-subscription-requirement-to-creator-monetization-standards/</guid><description>&lt;p>X &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/89a2260d081ba3c2d75305d173eb809eb1aaffbe">revised&lt;/a> its Creator Monetization Standards by replacing its reference to the Brand Safety Policies with the broader Content Monetization Policies, and by introducing a new eligibility condition. Creators must now have an active Premium, Premium Business, or Premium Organizations subscription to qualify for monetization. All other eligibility requirements, such as maintaining good standing and completing identity verification, remain unchanged.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>X ban using its content or API to fine-tune or train large AI models</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-ban-using-its-content-or-api-to-fine-tune-or-train-large-ai-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-ban-using-its-content-or-api-to-fine-tune-or-train-large-ai-models/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the Reverse Engineering and other Restrictions of use, X’s developer terms strictly banned using the X API or X Content to fine-tune or train a foundation or frontier model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/5453af28fd27c1ea2ba71a72ae0514bb4df9c384">restricting access to the data&lt;/a>, X was likely aiming to protect the competitive value of the tweets ensuring that only the company could use X’s content for developing and fine-tuning their own AI models. X could also potentially monetize its user-generated data through exclusive deals with chosen partners.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>X expands and restructures its Civic-Integrity Policy</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-expands-and-restructures-its-civic-integrity-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-expands-and-restructures-its-civic-integrity-policy/</guid><description>&lt;p>X has &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/d39ef3f9b09a5a4d9cacf999be20c6fd2047cfc6">revised&lt;/a> its Civic Integrity policy with substantial changes to how it defines civic processes and how it structures its rules against misleading or suppressive content. The update reorganizes the section under the new title “Civic Integrity” and introduces a clearer, more formal definition of what constitutes a civic process. X now explicitly lists political elections, censuses, major referendums, and ballot initiatives as events covered by the policy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The revised introduction outlines the policy’s purpose as addressing misleading content that could affect participation in elections or other civic processes, including information that may confuse users about how, when, or where to take part. This reframing moves the policy toward a more preventive orientation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>X forbids displaying content on the web</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-forbids-displaying-content-on-the-web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-forbids-displaying-content-on-the-web/</guid><description>&lt;p>X, formerly twitter, &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/0c181037266bee192f8956d536295699188e9549">introduced&lt;/a> a &amp;ldquo;prohibition on I-Framing&amp;rdquo; in its Developer Terms. Previously, users and developers could incorporate content from X on their websites but it is now forbidden to incorporate content &amp;ldquo;within an iframe, inline frame, or any similar embedding mechanism&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever since Elon Musk purchased X, its API has become more limited and very restrictive, in favour of a &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/2/2/23582615/twitter-removing-free-api-developer-apps-price-announcement">monetization model&lt;/a>. Before that, it was &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/c/features/23993135/twitter-breaking-news-history">celebrated&lt;/a> for its transparency and reliability for academic research and journalists.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>X no longer restricts shopping to US-based businesses</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-no-longer-restricts-shopping-to-us-based-businesses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/x-no-longer-restricts-shopping-to-us-based-businesses/</guid><description>&lt;p>X &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/e74e82155f06490f2bb7e21b6c118ba335cd4acc">updated&lt;/a> its rules regarding merchandise sales. It is no longer necessary to have a US-based business. It also allows state-affiliated media to sell merchandise. Selling merchandise was previously restricted to ‘Professional Account[s]’, but it’s now open to X Premium and X Premium accounts. Pricing can now be in local currency, not just in US dollars. The list of prohibited merchandise categories was extensively revised, but the scope of the policy remained unchanged.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube adds health data to the information prohibited from being published</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-adds-health-data-to-the-information-prohibited-from-being-published/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-adds-health-data-to-the-information-prohibited-from-being-published/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since April 12, YouTube &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/9d6c4832b8ff3de62b095b1b29c53d83c7722d27?diff=split&amp;short_path=0222544#">forbids&lt;/a> the disclosure of another person’s “personal” data, and not only one’s “confidential” data. The harassment section of its French community guidelines now adds “medical records” to the examples of information a user is prohibited from divulging about a third party.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube allows claims of fraud in Brazilian elections</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-allows-claims-of-fraud-in-brazilian-elections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-allows-claims-of-fraud-in-brazilian-elections/</guid><description>&lt;p>YouTube &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/40ef6fea4de2f8b21098cb390db286facb33f484">removed&lt;/a> an explicit prohibition regarding content advancing false claims about the integrity of past elections. The Brazilian presidential election was the last example in the guideline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous versions also &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/pga-versions/commit/9c526ada56c246f42b06d549a23f71577bfa9eba">included&lt;/a> the US presidential elections and German federal elections. YouTube &lt;a href="https://blog.youtube/inside-youtube/us-election-misinformation-update-2023/">announced&lt;/a> in 2023 that they would &amp;ldquo;stop removing content that advances false claims that widespread fraud, errors, or glitches occurred in the 2020 and other past US Presidential elections&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 2026 presidential election in Brazil will take place on October 4th. In the previous election in 2022, YouTube and Facebook were &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2022/oct/20/brazil-election-disinformation-youtube-facebook">reported&lt;/a> as platforms used for disseminating misinformation and voter suppression, despite their claims of significant resource allocation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube closes its fast-track content flagging program to individuals</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-closes-its-fast-track-content-flagging-program-to-individuals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-closes-its-fast-track-content-flagging-program-to-individuals/</guid><description>&lt;p>YouTube &lt;a target="_blank" rel="noopener" href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-elections-versions/commit/31605bd7408cdfe8c6362aa81ffa1d65a81dc2d8#diff-9c397c37c7e78e06148eed3f044d003da8f001e9149d65f3a08bbfdca997d612L103">changed&lt;/a> the presentation of its YouTube Trusted Flagger program, which offers more direct access to the platform to remove posts that violate its rules. It was until then intended for some NGOs, government agencies and users who effectively report content that violates the rules. It is now presented as open only to non-governmental organizations and public authorities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube details out criteria for educational, artistic, and public interest exceptions to violating content</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-details-out-criteria-for-educational-artistic-and-public-interest-exceptions-to-violating-content/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-details-out-criteria-for-educational-artistic-and-public-interest-exceptions-to-violating-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>YouTube &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/c2052c3843124de40812bd065df9a842a62137f4">expanded&lt;/a> on its criteria for exceptions to content violating community guidelines. It clarified that in some cases, content with educational, documentary, scientific, or artistic (EDSA) context including public interest content will be considered an exception to otherwise prohibited content. This was updated in several sections of the community guidelines including Nudity &amp;amp; Sexual Content Policy, Child Safety policy, Suicide, Self-Harm, and Eating Disorders policy, Harmful or Dangerous Content policy, Hate Speech policy, and Misinformation policies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube now allows promotion of colloidal silver</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-now-allows-promotion-of-colloidal-silver/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-now-allows-promotion-of-colloidal-silver/</guid><description>&lt;p>YouTube &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/1343610f78702cf24d071f623ab5eba02dad6d29#diff-9c397c37c7e78e06148eed3f044d003da8f001e9149d65f3a08bbfdca997d612L1988">removed&lt;/a> colloidal silver from the list of harmful substances that are not allowed to be promoted on YouTube both as prevention and treatment methods. This change was reflected in the Medical Misinformation section of its Community Guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colloidal silver consists of silver particles in liquid form, and is often &lt;a href="https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/colloidal-silver">advocated&lt;/a> as a dietary supplement and an alternative medicine for treatment of various infections and diseases. There is however, no clear scientific evidence to support these claims. In 1999, the United States Food and Drug Administration (FDA) &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/fullarticle/2214158">warned&lt;/a> that colloidal silver products are not recognised as safe and effective. There have also been &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/does-colloidal-silver-work/?_sp=d5ff2a97-5dc0-4534-acff-7e485950488b.1760138370827">reports&lt;/a> on the severe side-effects of long-term colloidal silver ingestion, causing a skin discolouration condition called argyria. Medical practitioners have &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2214750020304662#:~:text=No%20scientific%20evidence%20has%20been%20found%20for,some%20parts%20of%20the%20world%2C%20including%20Finland.">condemned&lt;/a> internet platforms in the past for not adhering to regulatory bodies, and popularising the use of colloidal silver.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube starts displaying AI-generated summaries of its policies</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-starts-displaying-ai-generated-summaries-of-its-policies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-starts-displaying-ai-generated-summaries-of-its-policies/</guid><description>&lt;p>YouTube &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/f11426bb31e453dd351f2ba77ad32eb7cc94b9bd">introduced&lt;/a> an “&lt;strong>AI-generated Key Takeaways&lt;/strong>” section in its Developer Terms. The new section provides a concise, bulleted summary of the primary obligations for developers, including requirements for lawful use, transparency, and data protection. The text is identified as AI-generated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The update reflects a growing practice of using large language models (LLMs) to simplify the communication of complex or technical policies. Similar approaches are emerging in other contexts, such as policy monitoring and&lt;a href="https://abovethelaw.com/2025/09/how-innovative-legal-teams-are-turning-ai-from-promise-to-practice/"> legal documentation&lt;/a>, where AI-generated summaries are used to improve accessibility for broader audiences. However, if an automated summary diverges from the official terms, responsibility for the discrepancy remains unclear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube updates gambling content rules, clarifies certification standards, and reframes dramatized violence guidance</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-updates-gambling-content-rules-clarifies-certification-standards-and-reframes-dramatized-violence-guidance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/youtube-updates-gambling-content-rules-clarifies-certification-standards-and-reframes-dramatized-violence-guidance/</guid><description>&lt;p>YouTube &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/vlopses-us-versions/commit/c9fe2e55daf85f2d829fafaa03c89bc099480a01">updated&lt;/a> its Community Guidelines to adjust wording around dramatized violence and online gambling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The platform replaced language describing “people being tortured, dismembered, or decapitated” with a broader reference to violence against non-combatants in its age-restriction criteria for fictional or dramatized content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>YouTube also changed its gambling rules to focus on online gambling sites not certified by Google, replacing prior references to unapproved gambling sites. Related examples were updated to clarify that content may depict or promote online gambling when it involves certified sites, and now also include social/sweepstakes casinos.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>