<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Impact model on Open Terms Archive website</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/</link><description>Recent content in Impact model on Open Terms Archive website</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Call for funders and contributors on generative AI industry</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/generative-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/generative-ai/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="proposal">Proposal&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The generative AI industry is a globally relevant target for Open Terms Archive, considering on the one hand that it is so emergent it is mostly unregulated and will thus evolve very fast; and on the other hand that its potential for societal transformation, disruption and harm are as immense as the new opportunities it will offer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the same time, several national and global regulatory proposals on AI exist, but none have been adopted yet: UNESCO’s “Ethics of AI”; Council of Europe’s “Convention of AI”; EU’s “AI Act”; White House’s “Blueprint for an AI Bill of Rights”; China’s “AI rulebook”; OECD “AI Principles”… Legal challenges on personal data handling arise, starting with Italy and France. The impact of these upcoming constraints will be observable in the evolution of the terms, and legislative drafting should be informed by the latest state of business affairs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Impact on compliance</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/compliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/compliance/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="achievements">Achievements&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>On 1 December 2023, the European Commission &lt;a href="https://digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/en/news/commission-launches-new-database-track-digital-services-terms-and-conditions">officially&lt;/a> launched a new &lt;a href="https://platform-contracts.digital-strategy.ec.europa.eu/index.html">database&lt;/a> based on Open Terms Archive to track the terms and conditions of digital services.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In November 2022, the European Commission has &lt;a href="https://op.europa.eu/en/publication-detail/-/publication/d6a287b5-5116-11ee-9220-01aa75ed71a1/language-en/">finalised a report&lt;/a> using Open Terms Archive to conduct a large-scale &lt;a href="https://ppmi.lt/news-insights/ppmi-has-completed-early-evaluation-p2b-regulation">assessment&lt;/a> of compliance with the &lt;a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg/2019/1150/oj">P2B Regulation&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In January 2022, Open Terms Archive was cited as example in support of the &lt;a href="https://www.lifewire.com/the-tldr-act-could-help-you-make-sense-of-terms-of-service-agreements-5216643">TLDR Act&lt;/a> (for &lt;em>Terms-of-service Labeling, Design, and Readability&lt;/em>), a US bill co-sponsored by &lt;a href="https://trahan.house.gov/">Congresswoman Lori Trahan&lt;/a> (D-MA-03), &lt;a href="https://www.cassidy.senate.gov/">Senator Bill Cassidy&lt;/a> (R-LA), and Senator Ben Ray Luján (D-NM) to enforce the publication of summaries of terms of use in machine-readable formats.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Since September 2020, the French &lt;a href="https://www.peren.gouv.fr/en/">Center of expertise for digital platform regulation&lt;/a> (PEReN) uses Open Terms Archive as part of its toolset.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Impact on consumer protection</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/consumer-protection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/consumer-protection/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="achievements">Achievements&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In the first quarter of 2022, France&amp;rsquo;s largest consumer protection association, &lt;a href="https://www.quechoisir.org">UFC-Que Choisir&lt;/a>, detected several irregularities in French online marketplaces thanks to Open Terms Archive tracking. They requested and obtained the &lt;a href="https://github.com/OpenTermsArchive/france-versions/commit/0184178ee2fffbd5283c50f114e3211667391b15">correction&lt;/a> of several non-functional links to cooling-off cancellation forms.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In January 2022, Open Terms Archive was used as an example of feasibility in the &lt;a href="https://trahan.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=2353">TLDR Act&lt;/a>, a bill presented to the US Congress aiming at forcing platforms to clarify their commitments towards end users.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Impact on mis- and disinformation</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/mis-and-disinformation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/mis-and-disinformation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mis- and disinformation are typically addressed through reactive measures against specific attacks or proactive prevention efforts. While these approaches are necessary and valuable, they are inherently endless and fail to address the root of the problem. Exploiting vulnerabilities for political gains will always attract malign actors, outnumbering those interested in prevention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The issue of disinformation arises from vulnerabilities in the tools that mediate the information environment.&lt;/strong> These vulnerabilities persist because fixing them conflicts with the economic incentives of large platforms. Therefore, it is crucial to increase the costs associated with leaving these vulnerabilities open and provide incentives for their resolution. Alternatively, obligations should be imposed on actors to compel them to address these vulnerabilities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Impact on personal data protection</title><link>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://opentermsarchive.org/en/impact/privacy/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="achievements">Achievements&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In September 2021, &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2021/09/06/protonmail-logged-ip-address-of-french-activist-after-order-by-swiss-authorities/">press articles&lt;/a> objectified their investigations with data from Open Terms Archive following the &lt;a href="https://opentermsarchive.org/en/memos/protonmail-clarifies-its-privacy-policies/">collaboration&lt;/a> of Swiss provider ProtonMail with law enforcement.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>